<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;somAkhyAdi on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;somAkhyAdi on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The visitation on the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-04-21_the-visitation-on-the-knoll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-04-21_the-visitation-on-the-knoll/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The visitation on the knoll
It was the time Somakhya and Indrasena were by themselves — without their companions — for that is close to the ultimate test of a man. At that point, they were working on the mysterious three-gene system coding for an ATPase that had evolved from a GTPase, a mystery protein, and a RNase. While they had made an initial incision they were being rebuffed by it and it was testing Indrasena’s skills to the utmost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The crossover with Dabba</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-03-10_the-chrossover-with-dabba-seTThiputta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-03-10_the-chrossover-with-dabba-seTThiputta/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The crossover with Dabba Seṭṭhīputta
Ash It was a Śivarātrī. Vidrum accompanied his friends Somakhya and Lootika to visit the small shrine of Rudra in the cemetery beside his house. It was one of the rare days when the normally deserted cemetery was fairly busy with many a votary streaming in to pay homage at the shrine. Vidrum milled around a bit as his friends performed some japa at the side of the circumambulatory circuit of the shrine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dalāl who became a</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-01-16_the-dalal-who-became-a-poltergeist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2024-01-16_the-dalal-who-became-a-poltergeist/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The Dalāl who became a poltergeist
Lootika had returned from a scientific competition, which had been held in the dreadful city of Mahāvisphoṭaka, like the victorious Roman army after sacking the towns of West Asian counter-religionists. To both celebrate and to educate the class her teacher had organized an evening of sky-watching where Lootika was to introduce her often unruly classmates to the basics of astronomy. She knew well that beauty and success inspired anger and envy in many and that such a session could descend into the unsavory or worse quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The death of Miss Lizzie</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2022-05-02_the-death-of-miss-lizzie-willink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2022-05-02_the-death-of-miss-lizzie-willink/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The death of Miss Lizzie Willink
Late that spring, Somakhya and Lootika were visited by their mleccha friend Irmhild. Letting her sleep off the jet lag, they left for work. Given the good weather, Lootika returned early to check on their friend and go out with her prospecting spiders in the nearby woods for their work on endosymbionts. L: “Hope you had some good sleep and are all set to lead our battle-charge?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The strange case of the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2021-11-27_the-strange-case-of-the-apastamba-sprite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/somAkhyAdi/2021-11-27_the-strange-case-of-the-apastamba-sprite/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The strange case of the Āpastamba sprite
Problem manifests This is the second of the two stories that arose from incidents during the visit of Yaśaśravas, Somakhya’s cousin. With the autumnal vacations, Somakhya was having a good time with his visiting cousin, giving him lectures on the theory and the practice of the study of variable stars. During the day, they spent their time with numerical solutions of differential equations that modeled the pulsations of stars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
