<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Zarathustra on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Zarathustra on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 INTRODUCTION BY MRS FORSTER–NIETZSCHE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/00_INTRODUCTION_BY_MRS_FORSTERNIETZSCHE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/00_INTRODUCTION_BY_MRS_FORSTERNIETZSCHE/</guid>
      <description>HOW ZARATHUSTRA CAME INTO BEING.
&amp;ldquo;Zarathustra&amp;rdquo; is my brother’s most personal work; it is the history of his most individual experiences, of his friendships, ideals, raptures, bitterest disappointments and sorrows. Above it all, however, there soars, transfiguring it, the image of his greatest hopes and remotest aims. My brother had the figure of Zarathustra in his mind from his very earliest youth: he once told me that even as a child he had dreamt of him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/01/</guid>
      <description>ZARATHUSTRA’S PROLOGUE. 1. When Zarathustra was thirty years old, he left his home and the lake of his home, and went into the mountains. There he enjoyed his spirit and solitude, and for ten years did not weary of it. But at last his heart changed,—and rising one morning with the rosy dawn, he went before the sun, and spake thus unto it:
Thou great star! What would be thy happiness if thou hadst not those for whom thou shinest!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/02/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;—and only when ye have all denied me, will I return unto you.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Verily, with other eyes, my brethren, shall I then seek my lost ones; with another love shall I then love you.&amp;quot;—ZARATHUSTRA, I., &amp;ldquo;The Bestowing Virtue.&amp;rdquo;
XXIII THE CHILD WITH THE MIRROR. After this Zarathustra returned again into the mountains to the solitude of his cave, and withdrew himself from men, waiting like a sower who hath scattered his seed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/03/</guid>
      <description>THIRD PART.
&amp;ldquo;Ye look aloft when ye long for exaltation, and I look downward because I am exalted.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Who among you can at the same time laugh and be exalted?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;He who climbeth on the highest mountains, laugheth at all tragic plays and tragic realities.&amp;quot;—ZARATHUSTRA, I., &amp;ldquo;Reading and Writing.&amp;rdquo;
XLV THE WANDERER. Then, when it was about midnight, Zarathustra went his way over the ridge of the isle, that he might arrive early in the morning at the other coast; because there he meant to embark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/zarathustra/04/</guid>
      <description>FOURTH AND LAST PART.
Ah, where in the world have there been greater follies than with the pitiful? And what in the world hath caused more suffering than the follies of the pitiful?
Woe unto all loving ones who have not an elevation which is above their pity!
Thus spake the devil unto me, once on a time: &amp;ldquo;Even God hath his hell: it is his love for man.&amp;rdquo;
And lately did I hear him say these words: &amp;ldquo;God is dead: of his pity for man hath God died.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
