<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 Book Two on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 Book Two on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>057</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/057/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/057/</guid>
      <description>To the realists. – You sober people who feel armed against passion and phantastical conceptions and would like to make your emptiness a matter of pride and an ornament – you call yourself realists and insinuate that the world really is the way it appears to you: before you alone reality stands unveiled, and you yourselves are perhaps the best part of it – oh, you beloved images of Sais!1 But aren’t you too in your unveiled condition still most passionate and dark creatures, compared to fish, and still all too similar to an artist in love?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>058</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/058/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/058/</guid>
      <description>Only as creators! – This has caused me the greatest trouble and still does always cause me the greatest trouble: to realize that what things are called is unspeakably more important than what they are. The reputation, name, and appearance, the worth, the usual measure and weight of a thing – originally almost always something mistaken and arbitrary, thrown over things like a dress and quite foreign to their nature and even to their skin – has, through the belief in it and its growth from generation to generation, slowly grown onto and into the thing and has become its very body: what started as appearance in the end nearly always becomes essence and effectively acts as its essence!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>059</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/059/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/059/</guid>
      <description>We artists. – When we love a woman, we easily come to hate nature because of all the repulsive natural functions to which every woman is subject; we prefer not to think about it at all, but when our soul for once brushes against these matters, it shrugs impatiently and, as just said, casts a contemptuous look at nature: we feel insulted; nature seems to intrude on our property and with the most profane hands at that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>060</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/060/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/060/</guid>
      <description>Women and their action at a distance. – Do I still have ears? Am I all ear and nothing else? Here I stand amidst the fire of the surf, whose white flames are licking at my feet: from all sides it is howling, threatening, screaming, shrieking at me, while the old earth-rattler2 sings his aria in the lowest of depths, deep as a roaring bull, while pounding such an earth-rattling beat that the hearts of even these weather-beaten monsters of the rocks are trembling in their bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>061</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/061/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/061/</guid>
      <description>In honour of friendship. – That the feeling of friendship was in antiquity considered the highest feeling, even higher than the most celebrated pride of the self-sufficient sage, indeed, as it were, as its sole and even holier sibling: this is very well expressed in the story of the Macedonian king who gave a world-despising Athenian philosopher a talent and got it back. ‘What?’ said the king, ‘Has he then no friend?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>062</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/062/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/062/</guid>
      <description>Love. – Love forgives the beloved even his lust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>063</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/063/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/063/</guid>
      <description>The woman in music. – Why do warm and rainy winds also bring on a musical mood and the inventive pleasure of melody? Are they not the same winds that fill the churches and give women thoughts of love?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>064</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/064/</guid>
      <description>Sceptics. – I am afraid that old women in their most secret heart of hearts are more sceptical than all men: they believe the superficiality of existence to be its essence, and all virtue and depth is to them merely a veil over this ‘truth’, the very desirable veil over a pudendum – in other words, a matter of decency and shame, and no more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>065</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/065/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/065/</guid>
      <description>Devotion. – There are noble women with a certain poverty of spirit who know no other way to express their deepest devotion than to offer their virtue and sense of shame: it is what they hold as their highest possession. And often this gift is accepted without incurring as profound an obligation as the donors suppose – a very melancholy story!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>066</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/066/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/066/</guid>
      <description>The strength of the weak. – All women are subtle at exaggerating their weaknesses; indeed they are inventive at weaknesses in order to appear as utterly fragile ornaments that are harmed by even a speck of dust: their way of living is supposed to remind men of their clumsiness and burden their conscience with this. Thus they defend themselves against the strong and ‘the law of the jungle’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>067</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/067/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/067/</guid>
      <description>Feigning oneself. – She loves him now and gazes ahead with such calm confidence, like a cow. But alas! What bewitched him was precisely that she seemed utterly changeable and unfathomable! He already had too much steady weather in himself! Wouldn’t she do well to feign her old character? To feign lovelessness? Isn’t that the counsel of – love? *Vivat comoedia!*6</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>068</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/068/</guid>
      <description>Will and willingness. – Someone took a youth to a wise man and said: ‘Look, he is being corrupted by women!’ The wise man shook his head and smiled. ‘It is men who corrupt women’, he exclaimed, ‘and the failings of women should be atoned for and set right in men – for man makes for himself the image (Bild) of woman, and woman shapes herself (bildet sich) according to this image (Bild)’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>069</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/069/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/069/</guid>
      <description>Capacity for revenge. – That someone cannot defend himself and therefore also does not want to – this is not enough to disgrace him in our eyes; but we have a low regard for anyone who has neither the capacity nor the good will for revenge – regardless of whether it is a man or a woman. Would a woman be able to hold us (or ‘enthrall’ us, as they say) if we did not consider her able under certain circumstances to wield a dagger deftly (any kind of dagger) against us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>070</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/070/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/070/</guid>
      <description>The women who master the masters. – A deep and powerful alto voice, such as one sometimes hears in the theatre, suddenly raises the curtain upon possibilities that we usually do not believe in. All at once we believe that somewhere in the world there could be women with lofty, heroic, royal souls, capable of and ready for grandiose retorts, resolutions, and sacrifices, capable of and ready for mastery over men, because in them the best of man aside from his sex has become an incarnate ideal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>071</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/071/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/071/</guid>
      <description>On female chastity. – There is something quite amazing and monstrous in the upbringing of upper-class women; indeed, maybe there is nothing more paradoxical. The whole world agrees that they should be brought up as ignorant as possible about matters erotic, and that one has to impart in their souls a deep shame in the face of such things and the most extreme impatience and flight at the merest suggestion of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>072</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/072/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/072/</guid>
      <description>Mothers. – Animals think differently about females than humans do; they consider the female to be the productive being. There is no paternal love among them, only something like love for the children of a beloved and a getting used to them. In their children females have a satisfaction of their desire to dominate, a possession, an occupation, something that is totally intelligible to them and can be prattled with: all this taken together is motherly love – it is to be compared to the love of an artist for his work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>073</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/073/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/073/</guid>
      <description>Holy cruelty. – A man holding a newborn in his hand approached a holy man. ‘What should I do with this child?’ he asked; ‘it is wretched, misshapen, and doesn’t have life enough to die’. ‘Kill it!’ shouted the holy man with a terrible voice; ‘kill it and hold it in your arms for three days and three nights to create a memory for yourself: thus you will never again beget a child when it is not time for you to beget’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>074</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/074/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/074/</guid>
      <description>The unsuccessful. – Those poor women are always unsuccessful who, in the presence of the one they love, become restless and insecure and talk too much: for men are most surely seduced by a certain secret and phlegmatic tenderness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>075</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/075/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/075/</guid>
      <description>The third sex. – ‘A small man is a paradox, but still a man; but small women seem to me, when compared to tall women, to belong to another sex’, said an old dancing master. A small woman is never beautiful – said old Aristotle.7</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>076</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/076/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/076/</guid>
      <description>The greatest danger. – Had there not always been a majority of men who felt the discipline of their heads – their ‘rationality’ – to be their pride, their obligation, their virtue, and who were embarrassed or ashamed by all fantasizing and debauchery of thought, being the friends of ‘healthy common sense’, humanity would have perished long ago! The greatest danger that hovered and still hovers over humanity is the outbreak of madness – that is, the outbreak of arbitrariness in feeling, seeing, and hearing; the enjoyment in the lack of discipline of the head, the joy in human unreason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>077</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/077/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/077/</guid>
      <description>The animal with a good conscience. – The vulgar element in everything that pleases in Southern Europe – be it Italian opera (e.g. Rossini and Bellini)8 or the Spanish adventure novel (most readily accessible to us in the French disguise of Gil Blas)9 – does not escape me; but it does not offend me, just as little as does the vulgarity that one encounters on a walk through Pompeii and basically even when reading any ancient book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>078</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/078/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/078/</guid>
      <description>What we should be grateful for. – Only artists, and especially those of the theatre, have given men eyes and ears to see and hear with some pleasure what each himself is, himself experiences, himself wants; only they have taught us to value the hero that is hidden in each of these everyday characters and taught the art of regarding oneself as a hero, from a distance and as it were simplified and transfigured – the art of ‘putting oneself on stage’ before oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>079</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/079/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/079/</guid>
      <description>The attraction of imperfection. – I see here a poet who, like some people, exerts a greater attraction through his imperfections than through all that reaches completion and perfection under his hand – indeed, his advantage and fame are due much more to his ultimate incapacity than to his ample strength. His work never wholly expresses what he really would like to express, what he would like to have seen: it seems as if he has had the foretaste of a vision, but never the vision itself – yet a tremendous lust for this vision remains in his soul, and it is from this that he derives his equally tremendous eloquence of desire and craving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>080</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/080/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/080/</guid>
      <description>Art and nature. – The Greeks (or at least the Athenians) liked to hear good speech; indeed, they had a greedy craving for it which distinguishes them more than anything else from the non-Greeks. And so they demanded even of passion on stage that it speak well, and submitted with delight to the unnaturalness of dramatic verse – after all, in nature, passion is so taciturn! So mute and bashful! Or when it finds words, so confused and irrational and a shame to itself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>081</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/081/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/081/</guid>
      <description>Greek taste. – ‘What is beautiful about that?’ said the surveyor after a performance of Iphigenia. ‘Nothing is proved in it!’16 Were the Greeks that far away from this taste? In Sophocles, at least, ‘everything is proved’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>082</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/082/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/082/</guid>
      <description>Esprit17 as un-Greek. – The Greeks are indescribably logical and simple in all their thought; at least in their long good age they never wearied of this, as so often do the French, who all too gladly take a little leap into the opposite and actually only endure the spirit of logic when, through a series of such small leaps into the opposite, it betrays its sociable civility, its sociable self-denial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>083</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/083/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/083/</guid>
      <description>Translations. – One can estimate the degree of an age’s historical sense from the way it makes translations and seeks to absorb past ages and books. The French of Corneille’s age19 as well as those of the Revolution seized Roman antiquity in a way we no longer dare to – thanks to our higher historical sense. And Roman antiquity itself: how violently and yet naively it laid its hand on everything good and lofty in the older Greek antiquity!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>084</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/084/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/084/</guid>
      <description>On the origin of poetry. – The lovers of what is fantastic in humans, who also advocate the view that morality is instinctive, reason as follows: ‘Supposing that usefulness has always been venerated as the supreme deity, then where in all the world does poetry come from? This act of making speech rhythm counteracts rather than contributes to the clarity of communication, and yet it has shot up and is still shooting up all over the earth like a mockery of all useful expediency!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>085</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/085/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/085/</guid>
      <description>The good and the beautiful. – Artists constantly glorify – they do nothing else – and in particular all those states and things reputed to give man the occasion for once to feel good, or great, or drunk, or merry, or well and wise. These select things and states, whose value for human happiness is considered certain and well-defined, are the artists’ objects: artists always lie in wait to discover such things and to draw them into the realm of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>086</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/086/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/086/</guid>
      <description>On theatre. – This day I had strong and elevated feelings again, and if on its eve I could have music and art, I know very well what music and art I would not like to have, namely, the kind that tries to intoxicate its audience and drive it to the height of a moment of strong and elevated feelings – an art for those everyday souls who in the evening look not like victors on triumphal chariots but rather like tired mules who have been whipped somewhat too often by life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>087</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/087/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/087/</guid>
      <description>On the vanity of artists. – I believe that artists often do not know what they can do best because they are too vain and have set their minds on something prouder than these small plants seem to be that are new, strange, and beautiful and really capable of growing to perfection on their soil. That which in the last instance is good in their own garden and vineyard is not fully appreciated by them, and their love and insight are not of the same order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>088</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/088/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/088/</guid>
      <description>Being serious about truth. – Being serious about truth! How differently people understand these words! The very same opinions and types of proof and scrutiny that a thinker may consider a frivolity in himself to which he has, to his shame, succumbed on this or that occasion – these very same views may give an artist who encounters them and lives with them for a while the feeling that he has now become deeply serious about truth and that it is admirable that he, as an artist, has at the same time the most serious desire for the opposite of appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>089</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/089/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/089/</guid>
      <description>Now and formerly. – What do all our art of artworks matter if we lose that higher art, the art of festivals! Formerly, all artworks were displayed on the great festival road of humanity, as commemorations and memorials of high and happy moments. Now one uses artworks to lure poor, exhausted, and sick human beings to the side of humanity’s road of suffering for a short lascivious moment; one offers them a little intoxication and madness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>090</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/090/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/090/</guid>
      <description>Lights and shadows. – Books and drafts mean different things to different thinkers: one has collected in a book the lights that he was able swiftly to steal and carry home from the rays of some insight that dawned on him; another is able to convey only the shadows, the after-images in grey and black, of that which built itself up in his soul the day before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>091</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/091/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/091/</guid>
      <description>Caution. – As is well known, Alfieri32 lied very much when he told his amazed contemporaries his life story. He lied from that despotism against himself which he also revealed in the way he created his own language and tyrannized himself into becoming a poet – he had finally found a severe form of sublimity into which he pressed his life and his memory: no doubt there was much agony in all this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>092</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/092/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/092/</guid>
      <description>Prose and poetry. – It is remarkable that the great masters of prose have almost always also been poets, be it publicly or only in secret, in the ‘closet’; and verily, one writes good prose only face to face with poetry! For this is an uninterrupted, courteous war with poetry: all its attractions depend on the fact that poetry is constantly evaded and contradicted; everything abstract wants to be presented as a prank against poetry and as if with a mocking voice; everything dry and cool is supposed to drive the lovely goddess into lovely despair; often there are rapprochements, reconciliations for a moment, and then a sudden leap back and derisive laugh; often the curtain is raised and a harsh light is let in just as the goddess is enjoying her dusks and muted colours; often the word is taken out of her mouth and sung according to a melody that makes her cover her refined ears with her refined hands – and so there are a thousand delights of this war, including defeat, of which the unpoetic, the so-called men of prose, know nothing at all – which is why they write and speak only bad prose!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>093</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/093/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/093/</guid>
      <description>But then why do you write? – A: I am not one of those who think with a wet quill in hand; much less one of those who abandon themselves to their passions right before the open inkwell, sitting on their chair and staring at the paper. I am annoyed or ashamed by all writing; to me, writing is nature’s call – to speak of it even in simile is repugnant to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>094</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/094/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/094/</guid>
      <description>Growth after death. – Those audacious little words about moral matters that Fontenelle threw out in his immortal Dialogues of the Dead37 were considered in his time to be paradoxes and games of a not wholly innocent wit; even the highest judges of taste and of the mind saw nothing more in it – indeed, maybe not even Fontenelle himself. Now something incredible transpires: these thoughts become truths! Science proves them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>095</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/095/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/095/</guid>
      <description>Chamfort.40 – That someone who knew humanity and the masses as well as Chamfort still joined the masses and did not stand aside in philosophical renunciation and defence, I can only explain as follows: one instinct in him was stronger than his wisdom and was never satisfied: his hatred of all nobility of blood; perhaps his mother’s old hatred, which was only too easy to explain and which he had sanctified through love of his mother – an instinct for revenge harking back to his boyhood, waiting for the hour to avenge his mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>096</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/096/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/096/</guid>
      <description>Two speakers. – Of these two speakers, the one can show the full rationality of his cause only when he abandons himself to passion: this alone pumps enough blood and heat into his brain to force his lofty intellect to reveal itself. The other attempts the same thing now and then – to present his cause with the help of passion, sonorously, violently, and captivatingly – but usually with little success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>097</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/097/</guid>
      <description>On the garrulousness of writers. – There is a garrulousness of rage – frequent in Luther, also in Schopenhauer. A garrulousness due to an exceedingly large supply of conceptual formulations, as in Kant. A garrulousness due to a delight in ever-new twists of the same thing: one finds this in Montaigne. A garrulousness of spiteful natures: whoever reads the publications of our time will recall two writers here. A garrulousness from a delight in good words and forms of language: not rare in Goethe’s prose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>098</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/098/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/098/</guid>
      <description>In praise of Shakespeare. – The most beautiful thing I can say in praise of Shakespeare as a human being is this: he believed in Brutus and didn’t cast a speck of suspicion on this type of virtue! To him he devoted his best tragedy – it is still called by the wrong name46 – to him and to the most dreadful epitome of lofty morality. Independence of soul! That’s what’s at stake here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>099</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/099/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/099/</guid>
      <description>Schopenhauer’s followers. – What happens when people of a higher culture and barbarians come into contact: the lower culture usually takes on the vices, weaknesses, and excesses of the higher culture, on which basis it feels a certain attraction to that culture and finally, by way of the acquired vices and weaknesses, accepts some overflow of the valuable force of the higher culture – one can also observe this nearby and without travelling to barbarian peoples, to be sure in a form that is somewhat over-refined and intellectualized and not so easily palpable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/100/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/100/</guid>
      <description>Learning how to pay homage. – Men have to learn to pay homage just as they have to learn to feel contempt. Anyone who breaks new paths and has led many people onto new paths discovers with amazement how clumsy and poor those many are at expressing their gratitude; indeed, how seldom gratitude is able to express itself at all. It is as though whenever gratitude wants to speak, something gets caught in her throat so that she just clears her throat and falls silent clearing her throat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/101/</guid>
      <description>*Voltaire.*65 – Wherever there was a court, there were laws of good speech and thus also laws of style for all who wrote. The language of the court, however, is the language of the courtier, who has no area of expertise and who forbids himself convenient technical expressions even in conversation about scientific matters because they smack of areas of expertise; that is why, in countries with a courtly culture, technical expressions and everything that betrays a specialist is considered a stylistic blemish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>102</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/102/</guid>
      <description>A word to the philologists. – That there are books so valuable and regal that entire generations of scholars are well employed when, through their efforts, these books are preserved in a pure and intelligible state – philology exists to reinforce this faith again and again. It presupposes that there is no dearth of those rare human beings (even if one doesn’t see them right away) who really know how to use such valuable books – probably those who themselves write or could write such books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>103</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/103/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/103/</guid>
      <description>On German music. – Today German music is, more than any other, the music of Europe only because it alone has given expression to the transformation that Europe underwent through the Revolution: only German composers know how to lend expression to animated masses of people; how to create that enormous artificial noise that doesn’t even have to be very loud – whereas for example Italian opera knows only choruses of servants or soldiers, but not ‘people’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>104</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/104/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/104/</guid>
      <description>On the sound of the German language. – We know where the German comes from that for a few centuries has been accepted as literary German. The Germans, with their reverence for everything that came from the court, have deliberately taken the chanceries as their model in everything they had to write, such as letters, documents, wills, and so forth. To write in the style of the chanceries was to write like the courts and the government – that was something distinguished compared to the German spoken in the city in which one happened to live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>105</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/105/</guid>
      <description>The Germans as artists. – When the German really works up a passion (and not merely the usual good will to passion!), he behaves as he must, and thinks no further about his behaviour. But the truth is that his behaviour is then very clumsy and ugly, as if lacking in tact and melody, so that the spectators merely have their own feelings of embarrassment or pathos and nothing more – unless he elevates himself into that state of sublimity and rapture, of which many passions are capable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>106</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/106/</guid>
      <description>Music as advocate – ‘I am thirsting for a master composer’, said an innovator to his disciple, ‘who can learn my thoughts from me and hereafter speak them in his language: that way I will better penetrate into people’s ears and hearts. With tones one can seduce people into every error and every truth: who could refute a tone?’ – ‘So you would like to be considered irrefutable?’ said his disciple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>107</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/2_Book_Two/107/</guid>
      <description>Our ultimate gratitude to art. – Had we not approved of the arts and invented this type of cult of the untrue, the insight into general untruth and mendacity that is now given to us by science – the insight into delusion and error as a condition of cognitive and sensate existence – would be utterly unbearable. Honesty would lead to nausea and suicide. But now our honesty has a counterforce that helps us avoid such consequences: art, as the good will to appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
