<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Ecce homo on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Ecce homo on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/00/</guid>
      <description>Author intro FRIEDRICH NIETZSCHE was born near Leipzig in 1844, the son of a Lutheran clergyman. He attended the famous Pforta School, then went to university at Bonn and at Leipzig, where he studied philology and read Schopenhauer. When he was only twenty-four he was appointed to the chair of classical philology at Basle University; he stayed there until his health forced him into retirement in 1879. While at Basle he made and broke his friendship with Wagner, participated as an ambulance orderly in the Franco-Prussian War, and published The Birth of Tragedy (1872), Untimely Meditations (1873–6) and the first two parts of Human, All Too Human (1878–9).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 HOW ONE BECOMES WHAT ONE IS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/01_HOW_ONE_BECOMES_WHAT_ONE_IS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/01_HOW_ONE_BECOMES_WHAT_ONE_IS/</guid>
      <description>FOREWORD 1 SEEING that I must shortly approach mankind with the heaviest demand that has ever been made on it, it seems to me indispensable to say who I am. This ought really to be known already: for I have not neglected to ‘bear witness’ about myself. But the disparity between the greatness of my task and the smallness of my contemporaries has found expression in the fact that I have been neither heard nor even so much as seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 WHY I AM SO WISE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/02_WHY_I_AM_SO_WISE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/02_WHY_I_AM_SO_WISE/</guid>
      <description>1 THE fortunateness of my existence, its uniqueness perhaps, lies in its fatality: to express it in the form of a riddle, as my father I have already died, as my mother I still live and grow old. This twofold origin, as it were from the highest and the lowest rung of the ladder of life, at once décadent and beginning – this if anything explains that neutrality, that freedom from party in relation to the total problem of life which perhaps distinguishes me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 WHY I AM SO CLEVER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/03_WHY_I_AM_SO_CLEVER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/03_WHY_I_AM_SO_CLEVER/</guid>
      <description>1 − WHY do I know a few more things? Why am I so clever altogether? I have never reflected on questions that are none − I have not squandered myself. − I have, for example, no experience of actual religious difficulties. I am entirely at a loss to know to what extent I ought to have felt ‘sinful’. I likewise lack a reliable criterion of a pang of conscience: from what one bears of it, a pang of conscience does not seem to me anything respectable… I should not like to leave an act in the lurch afterwards, I would as a matter of principle prefer to leave the evil outcome, the consequences, out of the question of values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 WHY I WRITE SUCH GOOD BOOKS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/04_WHY_I_WRITE_SUCH_GOOD_BOOKS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/04_WHY_I_WRITE_SUCH_GOOD_BOOKS/</guid>
      <description>1 I AM one thing, my writings are another. – Here, before I speak of these writings themselves, I shall touch on the question of their being understood or not understood. I shall do so as perfunctorily as is fitting: for the time for this question has certainly not yet come. My time has not yet come, some are born posthumously. – One day or other institutions will be needed in which people live and teach as I understand living and teaching: perhaps even chairs for the interpretation of Zarathustra will be established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 THE BIRTH OF TRAGEDY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/05_THE_BIRTH_OF_TRAGEDY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/05_THE_BIRTH_OF_TRAGEDY/</guid>
      <description>1 IN order to be just to ‘The Birth of Tragedy’ (1872) one will have to forget a few things. It made its effect and even exercised fascination through what was wrong with it − through its application to Wagnerism, as if this were a symptom of a beginning. That is what made this book an event in Wagner’s life: it was only from then on that great hopes surrounded the name Wagner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 THE UNTIMELY ESSAYS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/06_THE_UNTIMELY_ESSAYS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/06_THE_UNTIMELY_ESSAYS/</guid>
      <description>1 THE four untimely essays are altogether warlike. They demonstrate that I was no ‘Jack o’ Dreams’, that I derive pleasure from drawing the sword − also, perhaps, that I have a dangerously supple wrist. The first attack (1873) was on German culture, which even at that time I already looked down on with remorseless contempt. Without meaning, without substance, without aim: a mere ‘public opinion’. There is no more vicious misunderstanding than to believe that the Germans’ great success in arms could demonstrate anything in favour of this culture − not to speak of its victory over France… The second untimely essay (1874) brings to light what is dangerous, what gnaws at and poisons life, in our way of carrying on science −: life sick with this inhuman clockwork and mechanism, with the ‘impersonality’ of the worker, with the false economy of ‘division of labour’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 HUMAN, ALL TOO HUMAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/07_HUMAN_ALL_TOO_HUMAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/07_HUMAN_ALL_TOO_HUMAN/</guid>
      <description>With Two Supplements
1 ‘HUMAN, All Too Human’ is the memorial of a crisis. It calls itself a book for free spirits: almost every sentence in it is the expression of a victory − with this book I liberated myself from that in my nature which did not belong to me. Idealism does not belong to me: the title says: ‘where you see ideal things, I see − human, alas all too human things!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 DAYBREAK</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/08_DAYBREAK/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/08_DAYBREAK/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts about Morality as a Prejudice
I WITH this book begins my campaign against morality. Not that it smells in the slightest of gunpowder – quite other and more pleasant odours will be perceived in it, provided one has some subtlety in one’s nostrils. Neither big nor even small guns: if the effect of the book is negative, its means are all the less so, means from which the effect follows like a conclusion not like a cannon-shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 THE GAY SCIENCE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/09_THE_GAY_SCIENCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/09_THE_GAY_SCIENCE/</guid>
      <description>‘DAYBREAK’ is an affirmative book, profound but bright and benevolent. The same applies once again and in the highest degree to the gaya scienza: in practically every sentence of this book profundity and exuberance go hand in hand. A poem which expresses gratitude for the most wonderful month of January I have ever experienced – the entire book is a gift – betrays out of what a depth ‘science’ has here become gay:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 THUS SPOKE ZARATHUSTRA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/10_THUS_SPOKE_ZARATHUSTRA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/10_THUS_SPOKE_ZARATHUSTRA/</guid>
      <description>A Book for Everyone and No One
1 I SHALL now tell the story of Zarathustra. The basic conception of the work, the idea of eternal recurrence, the highest formula of affirmation that can possibly be attained − belongs to the August of the year 1881: it was jotted down on a piece of paper with the inscription: ‘6,000 feet beyond man and time’. I was that day walking through the woods beside the lake of Silva-plana; I stopped beside a mighty pyramidal block of stone which reared itself up not far from Surlei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 BEYOND GOOD AND EVIL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/11_BEYOND_GOOD_AND_EVIL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/11_BEYOND_GOOD_AND_EVIL/</guid>
      <description>Prelude to a Philosophy of the Future
1 THE task for the immediately following years was as clear as it could be. Now that the affirmative part of my task was done, it was the turn of the denying, the No-saying and No-doing part: the revaluation of existing values themselves, the great war – the evocation of a day of decision. Included here is the slow search for those related to me, for such as out of strength would offer me their hand for the work of destruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 GENEALOGY OF MORALS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/12_GENEALOGY_OF_MORALS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/12_GENEALOGY_OF_MORALS/</guid>
      <description>A Polemic
THE three essays of which this Genealogy consists are in regard to expression, intention and art of surprise perhaps the uncanniest things that have ever been written. Dionysos is, as one knows, also the god of darkness. – Each time a beginning which is intended to mislead, cool, scientific, even ironic, intentionally foreground, intentionally keeping in suspense. Gradually an increasing disquiet; isolated flashes of lightning; very unpleasant truths becoming audible as a dull rumbling in the distance – until at last a tempo feroce is attained in which everything surges forward with tremendous tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 TWILIGHT OF THE IDOLS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/13_TWILIGHT_OF_THE_IDOLS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/13_TWILIGHT_OF_THE_IDOLS/</guid>
      <description>How to Philosophize with a Hammer
1 THIS writing of fewer than 150 pages, cheerful and fateful in tone, a demon which laughs – the work of so few days I hesitate to reveal their number, is the exception among books: there exists nothing more rich in substance, more independent, more overthrowing – more wicked. If you want to get a quick idea of how everything was upsidedown before me, make a start with this writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 THE WAGNER CASE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/14_THE_WAGNER_CASE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/14_THE_WAGNER_CASE/</guid>
      <description>A Musicians’ Problem
1 IF one is to be fait to this writing one has to suffer from the destiny of music as from an open wound. – What is it I suffer from when I suffer from the destiny of music? From this: that music has been deprived of its world-transfiguring, affirmative character, that it is décadence music and no longer the flute of Dionysos… Supposing, however, that one in this way feels the cause of music to be one’s own cause, to be the history of one’s own suffering, one will find this writing full of consideration and mild beyond measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 WHY I AM A DESTINY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/15_WHY_I_AM_A_DESTINY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/15_WHY_I_AM_A_DESTINY/</guid>
      <description>1 I KNOW my fate. One day there will be associated with my name the recollection of something frightful – of a crisis like no other before on earth, of the profoundest collision of conscience, of a decision evoked against everything that until then had been believed in, demanded, sanctified. I am not a man, I am dynamite. – And with all that there is nothing in me of a founder of a religion – religions are affairs of the rabble, I have need of washing my hands after contact with religious people… I do not want ‘believers’, I think I am too malicious to believe in myself, I never speak to masses… I have a terrible fear I shall one day be pronounced holy: one will guess why I bring out this book beforehand; it is intended to prevent people from making mischief with me… I do not want to be a saint, rather even a buffoon… Perhaps I am a buffoon… And none the less, or rather not none the less – for there has hitherto been nothing more mendacious than saints – the truth speaks out of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 NOTES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/16_NOTES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/ecce_homo/16_NOTES/</guid>
      <description>FOREWORD heaviest demand. The forthcoming Revaluation of all Values – together with the effect it may be expected to produce – is presumably what is meant.
Nitimur in vetitum. We strive after the forbidden (Ovid).
‘It is the stillest… guide the world’. Quoted from Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Part Two: ‘The Stillest Hour’.
The figs are falling… sky and afternoon. Quoted from Zarathustra, Part Two: ‘On the Blissful Islands’.
décadent. Nietzsche employs, here and elsewhere, the French word, since none with precisely this meaning was available to him in German.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
