<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 Book Four on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 Book Four on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>276</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/276/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/276/</guid>
      <description>For the new year. – I’m still alive; I still think: I must still be alive because I still have to think. *Sum, ergo cogito: cogito, ergo sum.*1 Today everyone allows himself to express his dearest wish and thoughts: so I, too, want to say what I wish from myself today and what thought first crossed my heart – what thought shall be the reason, warrant, and sweetness of the rest of my life!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>277</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/277/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/277/</guid>
      <description>Personal providence. – There is a certain high point in life; once we have reached it we are, for all our freedom, once more in the greatest danger of spiritual unfreedom; and no matter how much we have confronted the beautiful chaos of existence and denied it all providential reason and goodness, we still have to pass our hardest test. For it is only now that the thought of a personal providence confronts us with the most penetrating force and the best advocate, appearance, speaks for it – now that we so palpably see how everything that befalls us continually turns out for the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>278</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/278/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/278/</guid>
      <description>The thought of death. – It gives me a melancholy happiness to live in the midst of this jumble of lanes, needs, and voices: how much enjoyment, impatience, desire; how much thirsty life and drunkenness of life comes to light every moment of the day! And yet things will soon be so silent for all these noisy, living, life-thirsty ones! How even now everyone’s shadow stands behind him, as his dark fellow traveller!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>279</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/279/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/279/</guid>
      <description>Star friendship. – We were friends and have become estranged. But that was right, and we do not want to hide and obscure it from ourselves as if we had to be ashamed of it. We are two ships, each of which has its own goal and course; we may cross and have a feast together, as we did – and then the good ships lay so quietly in one harbour and in one sun that it may have seemed as if they had already completed their course and had the same goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>280</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/280/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/280/</guid>
      <description>Architecture for those who wish to pursue knowledge. – One day, and probably soon, we will need some recognition of what is missing primarily in our big cities: quiet and wide, expansive places for reflection – places with long, high-ceilinged arcades for bad or all-too-sunny weather, where no shouts or noise from carriages can penetrate and where refined manners would prohibit even priests from praying aloud: a whole complex of buildings and sites that would give expression to the sublimity of contemplation and of stepping aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>281</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/281/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/281/</guid>
      <description>Knowing how to end. – Masters of the first rank are recognized by the fact that in matters great and small they know how to find an end perfectly, be it the end of a melody or a thought; of a tragedy’s fifth act or an act of state. The best of the second rank always get restless toward the end, and do not fall into the sea with such proud and calm balance as do, for example, the mountains at Portofino – where the bay of Genoa finishes its melody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>282</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/282/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/282/</guid>
      <description>Gait. – There are certain tricks of the spirit by which even great minds betray that they come from the mob or half-mob; the gait and stride of their thoughts especially plays the traitor: they cannot walk. Thus Napoleon too, was unable, to his great vexation, to walk in a princely and ‘legitimate’ fashion on occasions that really demanded it, such as great coronation processions; even there, he was always just the leader of a column – proud and hasty at the same time, and very conscious of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>283</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/283/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/283/</guid>
      <description>Preparatory human beings. – I welcome all the signs of a more virile, warlike age approaching that will above all restore honour to bravery! For it shall pave the way for a still higher age and gather the strength that the latter will need one day – the age that will carry heroism into the search for knowledge and wage wars for the sake of thoughts and their consequences. To this end we now need many preparatory brave human beings who surely cannot spring from nothingness any more than from the sand and slime of present-day civilization and urbanization: human beings who know how to be silent, lonely, determined, and satisfied and steadfast in invisible activities; human beings profoundly predisposed to look, in all things, for what must be overcome; human beings whose cheerfulness, patience, modesty, and contempt for great vanities is just as distinctive as their magnanimity in victory and patience with the small vanities of the defeated; human beings with a sharp and free judgement concerning all victors and the share of chance in every victory and glory; human beings with their own festivals, their own working days, their own periods of mourning, accustomed to command with assurance and equally prepared, when called for, to obey – in each case, equally proud, equally serving their own cause; more endangered, more fruitful, happier human beings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>284</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/284/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/284/</guid>
      <description>Faith in oneself. – Few people have faith in themselves – and of these few, some possess it as a useful blindness or partial eclipse of the mind (what would they behold if they could see the bottom of themselves!), while the rest have to acquire it. Everything good, fine, or great they do is first of all an argument against the sceptic inside them. They have to convince or persuade him, and that almost requires genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>285</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/285/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/285/</guid>
      <description>Excelsior.6 – ‘You will never pray again, never adore again, never again rest in endless trust; you refuse to let yourself stop to unharness your thoughts before any ultimate wisdom, goodness, or power; you have no perpetual guard and friend for your seven solitudes; you live without the view of a mountain-range with snow-capped peaks and fire in its heart; there is no avenger for you anymore, no final corrector of the text of your life; there is no more reason in what happens, no love in what will happen to you; no more resting place stands open for your heart in which to find and no longer seek; you arm yourself against any ultimate peace; you will the eternal recurrence of war and peace; – Man of renunciation, all of this you wish to renounce?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>286</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/286/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/286/</guid>
      <description>Interruption. – These are hopes; but what will you see and hear of them when you have not experienced splendour, ardour, and rosy dawn in your own souls? I can only remind – more I cannot do! To move stones, to turn animals into humans – is that what you want from me? Oh, if you are still stones and animals, you had better look for your Orpheus7 first!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>287</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/287/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/287/</guid>
      <description>Delight in blindness. – ‘My thoughts’, said the wanderer to his shadow, ‘should show me where I stand, but they should not betray to me where I am going. I love ignorance of the future and do not want to perish of impatience and premature tasting of things promised.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>288</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/288/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/288/</guid>
      <description>High spirits. – It seems to me that most people simply do not believe in elevated moods, unless it be for moments or fifteen-minute intervals at most – except for those few who experience an elevated feeling over a longer period. But to be the human being of one elevated feeling, the embodiment of a single great mood, has hitherto been a mere dream and enchanting possibility; as yet, history does not offer us any certain examples of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>289</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/289/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/289/</guid>
      <description>Get on the ships! – If one considers how an overall philosophical justification of one’s way of living and thinking affects each individual – namely, like a sun, warming, blessing, impregnating, shining especially for him; how it makes him independent of praise and blame, self-sufficient, rich, generous with happiness and good will; how it incessantly turns evil into good, brings all forces to bloom and ripen and keeps the petty, great weed of melancholy and moroseness from coming up at all – one exclaims longingly, in the end: Oh, how I wish that many such new suns would yet be created!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>290</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/290/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/290/</guid>
      <description>One thing is needful. – To ‘give style’ to one’s character – a great and rare art! It is practised by those who survey all the strengths and weaknesses that their nature has to offer and then fit them into an artistic plan until each appears as art and reason and even weaknesses delight the eye. Here a great mass of second nature has been added; there a piece of first nature removed – both times through long practice and daily work at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>291</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/291/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/291/</guid>
      <description>Genoa. – I have been looking at this city for a long time, at its villas and pleasure-gardens and the wide circumference of its inhabited heights and slopes, and in the end I must say: I see faces that belong to past generations; this region is dotted with images of bold and autocratic human beings. They have lived and wish to live on – that is what they are telling me with their houses, built and adorned to last for centuries and not for the fleeting hour: they were well disposed towards life, however badly disposed they often may have been towards themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>292</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/292/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/292/</guid>
      <description>To the preachers of morals. – I do not want to moralize, but to those who do, I give this advice: if you want eventually to deprive the best things and situations of all their worth, then keep talking about them the way you have been! Place them at the top of your morality and talk from morning till night about the bliss of happiness, the tranquillity of the soul, about justice and immanent retribution – the way you carry on, all these good things will finally attain a popularity and street-clamour of their own, but at the same time all the gold that was on them will have worn off through handling, and all the gold inside will have turned to lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>293</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/293/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/293/</guid>
      <description>Our air. – We know it very well: to those who glance at science as if passing it on a walk, in the manner of women and unfortunately also many artists, the severity of its service – this inexorability in matters great and small, this swiftness in weighing, judging, and passing judgement – has something dizzying and fear-inspiring. What frightens them especially is how the hardest is demanded and the best done despite the absence of praise and awards; rather, as among soldiers, what one mostly hears is almost exclusively reproaches and sharp reprimands – for doing things well is considered the rule, and failure the exception; yet here as everywhere else, the rule has a reticent mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>294</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/294/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/294/</guid>
      <description>Against the slanderers of nature. – I find those people unpleasant in whom every natural inclination immediately becomes a sickness, something disfiguring or even contemptible – they have seduced us into the belief that man’s natural inclinations are evil; they are the cause of our great injustice towards our nature, towards all nature! There are enough people who could well entrust themselves to their inclinations with grace and without care, but who do not for fear of the imagined ‘evil essence’ of nature!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>295</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/295/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/295/</guid>
      <description>Brief habits. – I love brief habits and consider them invaluable means for getting to know many things and states down to the bottom of their sweetnesses and bitternesses; my nature is designed entirely for brief habits, even in the needs of its physical health and generally as far as I can see at all, from the lowest to the highest. I always believe this will give me lasting satisfaction – even brief habits have this faith of passion, this faith in eternity – and that I am to be envied for having found and recognized it, and now it nourishes me at noon and in the evening and spreads a deep contentment around itself and into me, so that I desire nothing else, without having to compare, despise, or hate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>296</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/296/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/296/</guid>
      <description>A firm reputation. – A firm reputation used to be a thing of utmost utility; and wherever society is still ruled by herd mentality it is still today most expedient for everyone to act as if his character and occupation are unchangeable, even if basically they are not. ‘One can depend on him; he stays the same’: wherever society is threatened this is the type of praise that means the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>297</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/297/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/297/</guid>
      <description>Being able to contradict. – Everybody knows now that being able to stand contradiction is a high sign of culture. Some even know that the higher human being desires and invites contradiction in order to receive a hint about his own injustice of which he is as yet unaware. But the ability to contradict, the acquired good conscience accompanying hostility towards what is familiar, traditional, hallowed – that is better yet than both those abilities, and constitutes what is really great, new, and amazing in our culture; it is the step of all steps of the liberated spirit: who knows that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>298</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/298/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/298/</guid>
      <description>Sigh. – I caught this insight on the wing and quickly took the nearest shoddy words to fasten it lest it fly away from me. And now it has died of these barren words and hangs and flaps in them – and I hardly know any more, when I look at it, how I could have felt so happy when I caught this bird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>299</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/299/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/299/</guid>
      <description>What one should learn from artists. – What means do we have for making things beautiful, attractive, and desirable when they are not? And in themselves I think they never are! Here we have something to learn from physicians, when for example they dilute something bitter or add wine and sugar to the mixing bowl; but even more from artists, who are really constantly out to invent new artistic tours de force of this kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>300</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/300/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/300/</guid>
      <description>Preludes to science – So you believe the sciences would have emerged and matured, if they had not been preceded by magicians, alchemists, astrologers, and witches who with their promises and false claims created a thirst, hunger, and taste for hidden and forbidden powers? Indeed, infinitely more has had to be promised than can ever be fulfilled in order that anything at all be fulfilled in the realm of knowledge. Those things which now appear to us to be preludes and exercises preparatory to science were in the past certainly not practised and felt to be any such thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>301</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/301/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/301/</guid>
      <description>Delusion of the contemplative ones. – Higher human beings distinguish themselves from the lower by seeing and hearing, and thoughtfully seeing and hearing, immeasurably more – and just this distinguishes human beings from animals, and the higher animals from the lower. The world becomes ever fuller for someone who grows into the height of humanity; ever more baited hooks to attract his interest are cast his way; the things that stimulate him grow steadily in number, as do the kinds of things that please and displease him – the higher human being always becomes at the same time happier and unhappier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>302</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/302/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/302/</guid>
      <description>The danger of the happiest. – To have refined senses and a refined taste; to be accustomed to the exquisite and most excellent things of the spirit as one is to the proper and most usual food; to enjoy a strong, bold, audacious soul; to go through life with a calm eye and a firm step, always prepared for the most extreme situations – as for a feast and full of yearning for undiscovered worlds and seas, people, and gods; to hearken to all cheerful music as if brave men, soldiers, seafarers were perhaps seeking a short rest and merriment there – and in the deepest pleasure of the moment to be overcome by tears and the whole crimson melancholy of the happy: who would not like all of this to be his possession, his state!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>303</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/303/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/303/</guid>
      <description>Two happy ones. – Truly, despite his youth, this person knows how to improvise life and amazes even the keenest observer – for he never seems to make a mistake even though he constantly plays the riskiest game. It reminds one of those masters of musical improvisation to whose hands the listener would also like to ascribe a divine infallibility even though, like every mortal, they make a mistake here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>304</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/304/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/304/</guid>
      <description>By doing we forgo. – Basically I abhor every morality that says: ‘Do not do this! Renounce! Overcome yourself!’ But I am well disposed towards those moralities that impel me to do something again and again from morning till evening, and to dream of it at night, and to think of nothing else than doing this well, as well as I alone can! When one lives that way, one thing after another that does not belong to such a life drops off: without hate or reluctance one sees this take its leave today and that tomorrow, like the yellow leaves that every faint wisp of wind carries off a tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>305</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/305/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/305/</guid>
      <description>Self-control. – Those moralists who command man first and above all to gain control of himself thereby afflict him with a peculiar disease, namely, a constant irritability at all natural stirrings and inclinations and as it were a kind of itch. Whatever may henceforth push, pull, beckon, impel him from within or without will always strike this irritable one as endangering his self-control: no longer may he entrust himself to any instinct or free wing-beat; instead he stands there rigidly with a defensive posture, armed against himself, with sharp and suspicious eyes, the eternal guardian of his fortress, since he has turned himself into a fortress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>306</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/306/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/306/</guid>
      <description>Stoics and Epicureans. – The Epicurean seeks out the situation, the persons, and even the events that suit his extremely sensitive intellectual constitution; he forgoes the rest – that is, almost everything – because it would be too strong and heavy a diet. The Stoic, by contrast, trains himself to swallow stones and worms, glass shards and scorpions without nausea; he wants his stomach to be ultimately insensible to everything the chance of existence pours into him – he brings to mind the Arabian sect of the Assua that one encounters in Algiers:14 like these insensitive people, he likes to act out his insensitivity before an invited audience, which is precisely what the Epicurean gladly eschews – for he has his ‘garden’!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>307</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/307/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/307/</guid>
      <description>In favour of criticism. – Something you formerly loved as a truth or a probability now strikes you as an error; you cast it off and believe your reason has made a victory. But maybe that error was as necessary for you then, when you were still another person – you are always another person – as are all your present ‘truths’, like a skin that concealed and covered many things you weren’t allowed to see yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>308</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/308/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/308/</guid>
      <description>The history of every day. – What is the history of your every day? Consider the habits of which it consists: are they the product of innumerable little cowardices and lazinesses or of your courage and innovative reason? Different as the two cases may be, people could conceivably give you equal praise and you might actually benefit them equally either way. However, praise and benefit and respectability may be enough for those who want merely a good conscience – but not for you who scrupulously examine the inside of things and know about conscience!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>309</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/309/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/309/</guid>
      <description>From the seventh solitude. – One day the wanderer slammed a door shut behind him, came to a halt, and wept. Then he said: ‘This penchant and passion for what is true, real, non-apparent, certain – how it exasperates me! Why does this gloomy and earnest oppressor follow me of all people! I want to rest, but he won’t allow it. How many things seduce me to linger? Everywhere there are Armida’s gardens16 for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>310</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/310/</guid>
      <description>Will and wave. – How greedily this wave is approaching, as if it were trying to reach something! How it crawls with terrifying haste into the inmost crevices of the craggy gorge! It seems to be trying to arrive before someone else; something of value, of great value, seems to be hidden there. – And now it is returning, a bit more slowly but still quite white with excitement – is it disappointed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>311</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/311/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/311/</guid>
      <description>Refracted light. – One is not always brave; and when one gets tired, one of us, too, is likely one day to lament: ‘It is so hard to hurt people – why is it necessary! What good does it do us to live in seclusion when we don’t want to keep to ourselves what gives offence? Wouldn’t it be more advisable to live in the bustle and to do good to individuals as compensation for the sins that should and must be committed against everyone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>312</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/312/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/312/</guid>
      <description>My dog. – I have named my pain and call it ‘dog’ – it’s just as faithful, just as obtrusive and shameless, just as entertaining, just as clever as every other dog – and I can scold it and take my bad moods out on it the way others do with their dogs, servants, and wives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>313</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/313/</guid>
      <description>No image of torment. – I want to follow Raphael’s example and never paint another image of torment. There are enough sublime things; one does not have to seek sublimity where it lives in sisterhood with cruelty; anyway, my ambition would find no satisfaction if I wanted to make myself a sublime torturer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>314</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/314/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/314/</guid>
      <description>New domestic animals. – I want my lion and eagle around so that I can always have hints and forebodings to know how great or small my strength is. Must I look down on them today and fear them? And will the hour return when they look up at me – in fear?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>315</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/315/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/315/</guid>
      <description>On the last hour. – Storms are my danger: will I have my storm of which I perish, as Cromwell perished of his storm? Or will I go out like a light that no wind blows out, but that grew tired and sated with itself – a burned-out light? Or finally: will I blow myself out lest I burn out? –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>316</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/316/</guid>
      <description>Prophetic human beings. – You are not sensible to the fact that prophetic human beings are full of suffering; you simply think they have been granted a beautiful ‘gift’ that you yourselves probably would like to have – but I will express myself in a parable. How animals can suffer from electricity in the air and clouds! We see how certain species, for example, monkeys, have a prophetic insight about the weather (as one can observe even in Europe – and not only in zoos, but also on Gibraltar).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>317</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/317/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/317/</guid>
      <description>Retrospection. – While we are living each phase of our lives we rarely recognize its true pathos, but always see it as the only state that is now possible for us and reasonable and – to use some words and a distinction of the Greeks – thoroughly an ethos and not a pathos.18 Today a few notes of music called back to my memory a winter and a house and a most solitary life, as well as the feeling I lived with: I thought I could continue to live that way forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>318</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/318/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/318/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom in pain. – There is as much wisdom in pain as in pleasure: like pleasure, pain is one of the prime species-preserving forces. If it weren’t, it would have perished long ago: that it hurts is no argument against it – it is its essence. In pain I hear the captain’s command: ‘Pull in the sails!’ The hardy seafarer ‘Man’ must have learned to adjust the sails in a thousand ways; otherwise he would have gone under too quickly and the ocean would have swallowed him too soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>319</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/319/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/319/</guid>
      <description>As interpreters of our experiences. – One type of honesty has been alien to all religion-founders and such: they have not made their experiences a matter of conscience for their knowledge. ‘What did I really experience? What was going on inside and around me? Was my reason bright enough? Was my will turned against all deceptions of the senses and stalwart in warding off the fantastic?’ None of them has asked such questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>320</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/320/</guid>
      <description>On meeting again. – A.: Do I still understand you rightly? You are searching? Where is your corner and star within the real world? Where can you lie down in the sun so that an abundance of well-being comes to you, too, and your existence justifies itself? Let everyone do that for himself – you seem to me to be saying – and let everyone put out of his mind generalities and worries about others and about society!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>321</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/321/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/321/</guid>
      <description>New caution. – Let’s stop thinking so much about punishing, reproaching, and improving! We rarely change an individual; and should we succeed, something else may have been accomplished, unnoticed: we may have been changed through him! Let’s rather make sure our own influence on all that is to come balances and outweighs his influence! Let’s not struggle in a direct fight, which is what reproaching, punishing, and desiring to improve amount to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>322</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/322/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/322/</guid>
      <description>Parable. – Those thinkers in whom all stars move in cyclical orbits are not the deepest; he who looks into himself as into a vast space and bears galaxies within also knows how irregular galaxies are; they lead into the chaos and labyrinth of existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>323</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/323/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/323/</guid>
      <description>Luck in fate – Fate bestows on us the greatest distinction when it has let us fight for a time on our opponents’ side. Thus we are predestined for a great victory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>324</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/324/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/324/</guid>
      <description>In media vita.19 – No, life has not disappointed me. Rather, I find it truer, more desirable and mysterious every year – ever since the day the great liberator overcame me: the thought that life could be an experiment for the knowledge-seeker – not a duty, not a disaster, not a deception! And knowledge itself: let it be something else to others, like a bed to rest on or the way to one, or a diversion or a form of idleness; to me it is a world of dangers and victories in which heroic feelings also have their dance- and playgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>325</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/325/</guid>
      <description>What belongs to greatness – Who will attain something great if he does not feel in himself the power to inflict great pain? Being able to suffer is the least; weak women and even slaves often achieve mastery at that. But not to perish of inner distress and uncertainty when one inflicts great suffering and hears the cry of this suffering – that is great; that belongs to greatness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>326</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/326/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/326/</guid>
      <description>Soul-doctors and pain. – All preachers of morals, and all theologians, share one bad habit: they all try to talk people into thinking they are in a very bad way and need some severe, final, radical cure. And since humanity has for centuries far too eagerly lent its ear to these doctrines, something of this superstition of being very badly off has finally stuck, so that they are now only too ready to sigh and find nothing good in life and make sad faces together, as if life were really quite hard to endure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>327</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/327/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/327/</guid>
      <description>Taking seriously. – For most people, the intellect is an awkward, gloomy, creaking machine that is hard to start: when they want to work with this machine and think well, they call it ‘taking the matter seriously’ – oh, how taxing good thinking must be for them! The lovely human beast seems to lose its good mood when it thinks well; it becomes ‘serious’! And ‘where laughter and gaiety are found, thinking is good for nothing’ – that is the prejudice of this serious beast against all ‘gay science’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>328</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/328/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/328/</guid>
      <description>To harm stupidity. – Surely the creed concerning the reprehensibility of egoism, preached so stubbornly and with so much conviction, has on the whole harmed egoism (to the advantage of, as I will repeat a hundred times, the herd instincts!) – above all, by depriving egoism of its good conscience and telling us to seek in it the true source of all unhappiness. ‘Your selfishness is the reason your life is miserable (Unheil)’ – that was preached for millennia and, as I said, harmed selfishness and deprived it of much spirit, much cheerfulness, much inventiveness, much beauty; it made selfishness stupid and ugly and poisoned it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>329</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/329/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/329/</guid>
      <description>Leisure and idleness. – There is something of the American Indian, something of the savagery peculiar to the Indian blood, in the way the Americans strive for gold; and their breathless haste in working – the true vice of the new world – is already starting to spread to old Europe, making it savage and covering it with a most odd mindlessness. Already one is ashamed of keeping still; long reflection almost gives people a bad conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>330</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/330/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/330/</guid>
      <description>Applause. – A thinker needs no applause and clapping of hands provided he is sure of his own clapping of hands; he cannot do without that. Are there people who can dispense with that, too, and altogether with every kind of applause? I doubt it; and Tacitus, who did not slander the wise, said even of the wisest of men: quando etiam sapientibus gloriae cupido novissima excuitur23 – which for him means never.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>331</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/331/</guid>
      <description>Better deaf than deafened – Formerly one wanted to be talked about; that is no longer enough, since the market has grown too large – only a shout will do. As a result, even good voices shout themselves down, and the best goods are offered by hoarse voices; without the vendors’ cry and hoarseness there is no longer any genius. That is, to be sure, a bad epoch for a thinker; he must learn how to find his own quietude even between two noises, and pretend he is deaf until he really is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>332</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/332/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/332/</guid>
      <description>The evil hour. – Every philosopher has probably had an evil hour when he thought: What do I matter if people don’t accept my bad arguments, too? And then some malicious little bird flew over him and chirped: ‘What do you matter? What do you matter?’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>333</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/333/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/333/</guid>
      <description>What knowing means. – Non ridere, non lugere, neque detestari, sed intelligere!24 says Spinoza as simply and sublimely as is his wont. Yet in the final analysis, what is this intelligere other than the way we become sensible of the other three? A result of the different and conflicting impulses to laugh, lament, and curse? Before knowledge is possible, each of these impulses must first have presented its one-sided view of the thing or event; then comes the fight between these one-sided views, and occasionally out of it a mean, an appeasement, a concession to all three sides, a kind of justice and contract; for in virtue of justice and a contract all these impulses can assert and maintain themselves in existence and each can finally feel it is in the right vis-à-vis all the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>334</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/334/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/334/</guid>
      <description>One must learn to love. – This happens to us in music: first one must learn to hear a figure and melody at all, to detect and distinguish it, to isolate and delimit it as a life in itself; then one needs effort and good will to stand it despite its strangeness; patience with its appearance and expression, and kindheartedness about its oddity. Finally comes a moment when we are used to it; when we expect it; when we sense that we’d miss it if it were missing; and now it continues relentlessly to compel and enchant us until we have become its humble and enraptured lovers, who no longer want anything better from the world than it and it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>335</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/335/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/335/</guid>
      <description>Long live physics! – So, how many people know how to observe? And of these few, how many to observe themselves? ‘Everyone is farthest from himself’25 – every person who is expert at scrutinizing the inner life of others knows this to his own chagrin; and the saying, ‘Know thyself’, addressed to human beings by a god, is near to malicious.26 That self-observation is in such a bad state, however, is most clearly confirmed by the way in which nearly everyone speaks of the nature of a moral act – that quick, willing, convinced, talkative manner, with its look, its smile, its obliging eagerness!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>336</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/336/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/336/</guid>
      <description>Nature’s stinginess. – Why has nature been so miserly towards humans that it did not allow them to shine – one more brightly, the other less so, each according to his inner magnitude of light? Why are great human beings not as beautifully visible in their own rising and setting as the sun? How much more unambiguous this would make life among men!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>337</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/337/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/337/</guid>
      <description>The ‘humanity’ of the future. – When I view this age with the eyes of a distant age, I can find nothing odder in present-day man than his peculiar virtue and disease called ‘the sense for history’. This is the beginning of something completely new and strange in history: if one gave this seed a few centuries and more, it might ultimately become a wonderful growth with an equally wonderful smell that could make our old earth more agreeable to inhabit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>338</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/338/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/338/</guid>
      <description>The will to suffer and those who feel compassion. – Is it good for you yourselves to be above all else compassionate persons? And is it good for those who suffer if you are compassionate? But let us leave the first question unanswered for a moment. What we most deeply and most personally suffer from is incomprehensible and inaccessible to nearly everyone else; here we are hidden from our nearest, even if we eat from the same pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>339</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/339/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/339/</guid>
      <description>Vita femina.28 – Not even all knowledge and all good will suffice for seeing the ultimate beauties of a work; it requires the rarest of lucky accidents for the clouds that veil the peaks to lift for us momentarily and for the sun to shine on them. Not only must we stand in just the right spot to see this, but our own soul, too, must itself have pulled the veil from its heights and must have been in need of some external expression and parable, as if it needed a hold in order to retain control of itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>340</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/340/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/340/</guid>
      <description>*The dying Socrates.*30 – I admire the courage and wisdom of Socrates in everything he did, said – and did not say. This mocking, love-sick monster and pied piper of Athens, who made the most audacious youths of Athens tremble and sob, was not only the wisest chatterer of all time; he was equally great in silence. I wish he had remained silent also in the last moments of his life – perhaps he would then belong to a still higher order of minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>341</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/341/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/341/</guid>
      <description>The heaviest weight. –
What if some day or night a demon were to steal into your loneliest loneliness and say to you:
‘This life as you now live it and have lived it
you will have to live once again and innumerable times again;
and there will be nothing new in it,
but every pain and every joy and every thought and sigh and everything unspeakably small or great in your life must return to you,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>342</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/342/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/4_Book_Four/342/</guid>
      <description>Incipit tragoedia.32 – When Zarathustra33 was thirty years old, he left his homeland and Lake Urmi and went into the mountains. There he enjoyed his spirit and solitude, and did not tire of that for ten years. But at last his heart changed – and one morning he arose with rosy dawn, stepped before the sun, and spoke to it thus: ‘You great heavenly body! What would your happiness be if you did not have those for whom you shine!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
