<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 KUNDALINI on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 KUNDALINI on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Self-Identification</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/01_Self-Identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/01_Self-Identification/</guid>
      <description>“Actually there is no difference betwen the Kundalini Shakti and Adya, the original Shakti of the universe, except that the Kundalini Shakti has become individualized.”
Vimalananda was not one to repeat himself; as soon as he began to speak about something of interest to me I was expected to drop whatever I was doing and listen. Usually he picked moments when I was engrossed in some mundane matter like reading the newspaper, since drawing my atten tion to his words would disengage my mind at least temporarily from its attachment to the mundane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Coverings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/02_Coverings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/02_Coverings/</guid>
      <description>“While Kundalini sleeps in the Muladhara Chakra at the base of the spine you are awake to the world and asleep to reality. When She awakes to unite with Her Shiva in your brain then you wake up to reality; you &amp;lsquo;fall asleep&amp;rsquo; to the world. An ignorant person believes that he is in the world; his Kundalini self-identifies with the poison of Maya. A jnani, one who knows, says rather, ‘The world is in me,&amp;rsquo; because his Kundalini self-identifies with Shiva.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Nadis and Chakras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/03_Nadis_and_Chakras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/03_Nadis_and_Chakras/</guid>
      <description>“The ego or ahamkara does not actually reside in the physical body, because the ego is not at all physical. It resides in the subtle body, and moves in the nadis, the ethereal nerves. The body&amp;rsquo;s 72,000 nadis act as con duits for prana, which is closely related to the ego. Numerologically, 72,000 means 7 + 2 = 9: the Nine Doors through which prana can enter or leave the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 The Nine Chakras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/04_The_Nine_Chakras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/04_The_Nine_Chakras/</guid>
      <description>“Most people will tell you there are six chakras. An Aghori will tell you there are nine. To understand this statement you must at least know the dif ference between a nara (man) and a khara (donkey). If you think this is a joking matter, it is because you are a khara yourself.”
I had grinned at the comparison, and now I grinned at his affront. He snorted and went on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Raising Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/05_Raising_Kundalini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/05_Raising_Kundalini/</guid>
      <description>I had to shake my head in appreciation and agreement, it was so true.
“To make Kundalini rise from the tip of the spine you must create enough pressure to force Her out of the Muladhara Chakra. The upward motion will continue only so long as the pressure remains; without it Kundalini drops back down to the bottom, due to gravity. Because humans stand erect, grav ity acts only on the tip of the spinal cord, not on the whole thing as it does in other animals, whose spines are horizontal or nearly so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Samadhi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/06_Samadhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/06_Samadhi/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I have always said that life is a memory. There are actually two types of memory: conscious and unconscious. The conscious memory is very fickle and inconstant; it is directed outwards towards mundane objects, which are temporary and transitory but seem eternal to the ignorant mind. The unconscious memory is permanent; it has been collecting all your karmas from tens of millions of births without any lapse or distortion. So the uncon scious memory is actually conscious, since it perfectly records everything that happens to you, and the conscious memory is actually unconscious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Kula Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/07_Kula_Kundalini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/07_Kula_Kundalini/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If you hope to continue to exist after Kundalini is awakened completely you must be able to make Her go from the Muladhara to the Sahasrara, and then in the reverse direction, downwards from the Sahasrara to the
( 771
AGHORA II: Kundalini
Muladhara, under perfect control. Prana and Apana are then perfectly united. Apana is represented as a downward-pointing triangle, and Prana as an upward-pointing one. Their union forms a six-pointed star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 The Snake</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/08_The_Snake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/08_The_Snake/</guid>
      <description>As Joseph Campbell documents in his book The Inner Reaches of Outer Space, the force that the Tantras call Kundalini has been represented as a ser pent in many world cultures, including the Sumerian, Chinese, ancient Irish, Aztec and Greek (the caduceus). Images of Kundalini as the Serpent Power predominantly reflect Her power of possessiveness, of Maya. Indian cosmology describes seven netherworlds beneath the surface of the earth in which dwell asuras (the &amp;ldquo;selfish&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;jealous” gods) and nagas (semi-divine snake beings).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 The Chakras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/09_The_Chakras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/09_The_Chakras/</guid>
      <description>Even though the chakras of the subtle body have been identified by other cultures, such as the ancient Egyptian and the Navajo, they have never been directly introduced into popular religion, for good reason. Having our Kun dalinis unawakened and our chakras closed is a form of protection; exist ence is possible for embodied beings solely because their chakras are
1831
AGHORA II: Kundalini
normally blocked. In fact, many Kundalini-generated disorders are due not to the blockage of a chakra but to the lack of blockage thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Kula Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/10_Kula_Kundalini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/02_KUNDALINI/10_Kula_Kundalini/</guid>
      <description>The fourth, fifth and sixth chapters of the book of I Samuel describe the capture by the Philistines and the eventual return to Israel of the Ark of the
[84]
KUNDALINI
Covenant. While it is difficult to draw direct correlations between otherwise unrelated ancient cultures, it is striking to note that during the period that the Philistines possessed the Ark the idol of their god Dagon was mysteri ously toppled and disfigured, and the entire population was struck low with hemorrhoids.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
