<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Book Three on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Book Three on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>108</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/108/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/108/</guid>
      <description>New battles. – After Buddha was dead, they still showed his shadow in a cave for centuries – a tremendous, gruesome shadow. God is dead; but given the way people are, there may still for millennia be caves in which they show his shadow. – And we – we must still defeat his shadow as well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>109</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/109/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/109/</guid>
      <description>Let us beware. – Let us beware of thinking that the world is a living being. Where would it stretch? What would it feed on? How could it grow and procreate? After all, we know roughly what the organic is; are we then supposed to reinterpret what is inexpressibly derivative, late, rare, accidental, which we perceive only on the crust of the earth, as something essential, common, and eternal, as those people do who call the universe an organism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>110</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/110/</guid>
      <description>Origin of knowledge. – Through immense periods of time, the intellect produced nothing but errors; some of them turned out to be useful and species-preserving; those who hit upon or inherited them fought their fight for themselves and their progeny with greater luck. Such erroneous articles of faith, which were passed on by inheritance further and further, and finally almost became part of the basic endowment of the species, are for example: that there are enduring things; that there are identical things; that there are things, kinds of material, bodies; that a thing is what it appears to be; that our will is free; that what is good for me is also good in and for itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>111</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/111/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/111/</guid>
      <description>The origin of the logical. – What is the origin of logic in man’s head? Surely it arose out of the illogical, the realm of which must originally have been immense. But innumerable beings drew inferences in a way different from that in which we do now perished; nonetheless, they might have been closer to the truth! He, for instance, who did not know how to find ‘identity’ often enough, both with regard to nourishment and to hostile animals – that is, he who subsumed too slowly and was too cautious in subsumption – had a slighter probability of survival than he who in all cases of similarity immediately guessed that they were identical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>112</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/112/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/112/</guid>
      <description>Cause and effect. – We call it ‘explanation’, but ‘description’ is what distinguishes us from older stages of knowledge and science. We are better at describing – we explain just as little as all our predecessors. We have uncovered a diverse succession where the naive man and investigator of older cultures saw only two different things, ‘cause’ and ‘effect’, as they said; we have perfected the picture of becoming but haven’t got over, got behind the picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>113</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/113/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/113/</guid>
      <description>On the doctrine of poisons. – So much has to come together in order for scientific thought to originate, and all these necessary forces have had to be separately invented, practised, cultivated! In their separateness they have, however, very often had a totally different effect from that which they have today when in the realm of scientific thought they mutually limit and keep each other in check: they have worked as poisons, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>114</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/114/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/114/</guid>
      <description>The scope of the moral. – As soon as we see a new picture, we immediately construct it with the help of all the old experiences we have had depending on the degree of our honesty and justice. There are no experiences other than moral ones, not even in the realm of sense perception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>115</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/115/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/115/</guid>
      <description>The four errors. – Man has been educated by his errors: first, he saw himself only incompletely; secondly, he endowed himself with fictitious attributes; thirdly, he placed himself in a false rank order in relation to animals and nature; fourthly, he invented ever new tables of goods and for a time took them to be eternal and unconditioned – so that now this, now that human drive and condition occupied first place and was ennobled as a result of this valuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>116</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/116/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/116/</guid>
      <description>Herd instinct. – Wherever we encounter a morality, we find an evaluation and ranking of human drives and actions. These evaluations and rankings are always the expression of the needs of a community and herd: that which benefits it the most – and second most, and third most – is also the highest standard of value for all individuals. With morality the individual is instructed to be a function of the herd and to ascribe value to himself only as a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>117</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/117/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/117/</guid>
      <description>Herd pangs of conscience. – During the longest and most remote periods of time there was a kind of pang of conscience completely different from that which exists now. Today one feels responsible only for what one wants and does, and finds one’s pride in oneself: all our teachers of justice start from this feeling of self and pleasure in the individual (des Einzelnen), as if the spring of justice (des Rechts)2 had always arisen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>118</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/118/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/118/</guid>
      <description>Benevolence. – Is it virtuous when a cell transforms itself into a function of a stronger cell? It has to. And is it evil when the stronger cell assimilates the weaker? It also has to; this is necessary for it, since it strives for superabundant replenishment and wants to regenerate itself. Accordingly one should make a distinction in benevolence between the drive to appropriate and the drive to submit, depending on whether it is the stronger or the weaker who experiences it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>119</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/119/</guid>
      <description>No altruism! – In many people I see a surplus strength and pleasure in wanting to become a function; they press towards and have the most delicate sense for all places where precisely they can be a function. Here belong those women who turn themselves into some function of a man that is especially weakly developed in him, and to that extent become his purse or his politics or his sociability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>120</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/120/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/120/</guid>
      <description>Health of the soul. – The popular medical formulation of morality (the originator of which is Ariston of Chios), ‘virtue is the health of the soul’,3 would, in order to be useful, have to be changed at least to read, ‘your virtue is the health of your soul’. For there is no health as such, and all attempts to define such a thing have failed miserably. Deciding what is health even for your body depends on your goal, your horizon, your powers, your impulses, your mistakes and above all on the ideals and phantasms of your soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>121</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/121/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/121/</guid>
      <description>Life not an argument. – We have arranged for ourselves a world in which we are able to live – by positing bodies, lines, planes, causes and effects, motion and rest, form and content; without these articles of faith no one could endure living! But that does not prove them. Life is not an argument; the conditions of life might include error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>122</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/122/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/122/</guid>
      <description>Moral scepticism in Christianity. – Christianity, too, has made a great contribution to enlightenment: it taught moral scepticism in an extremely trenchant and effective way – accusing, embittering, but with untiring patience and refinement; it annihilated in every single man the faith in his ‘virtues’. It caused those great virtuous men, of whom there was no dearth in antiquity, to disappear forever from the face of the earth – those popular men who with a faith in their own perfection went about with the dignity of a toreador.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>123</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/123/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge more than a means. – Even without this new passion – I mean the passion for knowledge – science would be promoted: up to now science has grown and matured without it. The good faith in science, the prejudice in its favour that rules our modern states (and formerly even the Church), is essentially based on the fact that this unconditional tendency and urge has manifested itself in science so rarely and that science is specifically regarded not as a passion but as a condition and ‘ethos’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>124</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/124/</guid>
      <description>In the horizon of the infinite. – We have forsaken the land and gone to sea! We have destroyed the bridge behind us – more so, we have demolished the land behind us! Now, little ship, look out! Beside you is the ocean; it is true, it does not always roar, and at times it lies there like silk and gold and dreams of goodness. But there will be hours when you realize that it is infinite and that there is nothing more awesome than infinity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>125</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/125/</guid>
      <description>The madman. – Haven’t you heard of that madman who in the bright morning lit a lantern and ran around the marketplace crying incessantly, ‘I’m looking for God! I’m looking for God!’ Since many of those who did not believe in God were standing around together just then, he caused great laughter. Has he been lost, then? asked one. Did he lose his way like a child? asked another. Or is he hiding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>126</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/126/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/126/</guid>
      <description>Mystical explanations – Mystical explanations are considered deep; the truth is, they are not even shallow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>127</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/127/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/127/</guid>
      <description>Aftereffects of the oldest religiosity. – Every thoughtless person believes that the will alone is effective; that willing is something simple, absolutely given, underivable, and intelligible in itself. When he does something, e.g. strikes something, he is convinced that it is he who is striking, and that he did the striking because he wanted to strike. He does not even notice a problem here; the feeling of will suffices for him to assume cause and effect, but also to believe that he understands their relation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>128</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/128/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/128/</guid>
      <description>The value of prayer. – Prayer has been invented for people who never really have thoughts of their own and who know no elevation of the soul or do not notice it if it occurs: what are such people to do in sacred places or in all important situations in life that demand calm and a kind of dignity? In order that they at least do not disturb, the wisdom of all founders of religions, small as well as great, has prescribed to them the formulas of prayer as a long mechanical work of the lips, combined with exertion of the memory and a same fixed posture of hands and feet and eyes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>129</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/129/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/129/</guid>
      <description>The conditions for God. – ‘God himself cannot exist without wise people’, said Luther,15 and with good reason; but ‘God can exist even less without unwise people’ – that our good Luther did not say!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>130</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/130/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/130/</guid>
      <description>A dangerous decision. – The Christian decision to find the world ugly and bad has made the world ugly and bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>131</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/131/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/131/</guid>
      <description>Christianity and suicide. – When Christianity came into existence the inclination to suicide was very strong – Christianity turned it into a lever of its power: it allowed only two kinds of suicide, dressed them up with the highest dignity and the highest hopes and forbade all others in a terrible manner. But martyrdom and the ascetic’s slow suicide were permitted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>132</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/132/</guid>
      <description>Against Christianity. – What decides against Christianity now is our taste, not our reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>133</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/133/</guid>
      <description>Principle. – An inescapable hypothesis to which humanity must have recourse again and again is still more powerful in the long run than the best believed faith in something untrue (such as the Christian faith). In the long run: that means here a hundred thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>134</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/134/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/134/</guid>
      <description>Pessimists as victims. – Wherever a deep dissatisfaction with existence comes to prevail, it is the aftereffects of some great dietary mistake made by a people over a long time that are coming to light. Thus the spread of Buddhism (not its origin) depended greatly on the Indians’ excessive and almost exclusive diet of rice and the general enervation resulting from it. Perhaps the modern European discontent is due to the fact that our prehistory, the entire middle ages, was given to drinking thanks to the influence of Germanic tastes on Europe: the middle ages means the alcohol poisoning of Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>135</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/135/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/135/</guid>
      <description>Origin of sin. – Sin, as it is now experienced wherever Christianity reigns or once reigned: sin is a Jewish feeling and a Jewish invention; and given that this is the background of all Christian morality, Christianity can be said to have aimed at ‘Judaizing’ the whole world. The extent to which this has succeeded in Europe is best brought out by how alien Greek antiquity – a world without feelings of sin – strikes our sensibility as being, despite all the good will expended by entire generations and many excellent individuals to approach and incorporate this world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>136</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/136/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/136/</guid>
      <description>The chosen people. – The Jews, who feel they are the chosen people of all peoples precisely because they are the moral genius of all peoples (owing to their ability more profoundly to despise the human being in themselves than any other people) – the Jews take a pleasure in their divine monarch and the holy which is similar to that which the French nobility took in Louis XIV. This nobility had surrendered all its power and sovereignty and had become contemptible: in order not to feel this, in order to be able to forget this, there was a need for a royal splendour, a royal authority and plenitude of power without equal to which only the nobility had access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>137</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/137/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/137/</guid>
      <description>Speaking in a parable. – A Jesus Christ was possible only in a Jewish landscape – I mean one over which the gloomy and sublime thunder clouds of the wrathful Jehovah hovered continually. Here alone was the rare and sudden piercing of a single sunbeam through the gruesome general and perpetual day-night experienced as a miracle of ‘love’, as the ray of the most undeserved ‘grace’. Only here could Christ dream of his rainbow and his heavenly ladder on which God descended to man; everywhere else good weather and sunshine were too much of a rule and everyday occurrence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>138</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/138/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/138/</guid>
      <description>Christ’s error. – The founder of Christianity thought that there was nothing from which men suffered more than their sins. That was his error – the error of one who felt himself free of sin and who lacked experience of it! Thus his soul filled itself with that wonderful fantastic compassion for a torment that was rarely a very great torment even among his people, who invented sin! But the Christians have found a way of retroactively vindicating their master and of sanctifying his error into ‘truth’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>139</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/139/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/139/</guid>
      <description>The colour of the passions. – People like St Paul have an ‘evil eye’ for the passions: they come to know only what is dirty, disfiguring, and heartbreaking about them; hence their ideal impulse seeks the annihilation of the passions, which they see totally purified in the divine. Quite unlike St Paul and the Jews, the Greeks turned their ideal impulse precisely towards the passions and loved, elevated, gilded and deified them; evidently passion made them feel not only happier but also purer and more divine than usual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>140</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/140/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/140/</guid>
      <description>Too Jewish. – If God wanted to become an object of love, he should first of all have had to give up judging and justice: a judge, even a merciful one, is no object of love. The founder of Christianity lacked delicacy of feeling in this regard, being a Jew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>141</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/141/</guid>
      <description>Too oriental. – What? A god who loves men provided that they believe in him and who casts evil gazes and threats at anyone who does not believe in this love? What? A love hemmed in by conditions as the feeling of an almighty god? A love that has not even mastered the feeling of honour and roused vengefulness? How oriental this all is! ‘If I love you, what does that concern you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>142</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/142/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/142/</guid>
      <description>Incense. – Buddha says: ‘Don’t flatter your benefactors!’ Repeat this saying in a Christian church and it will instantly clear the air of everything Christian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>143</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/143/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/143/</guid>
      <description>The greatest advantage of polytheism. – For an individual to posit his own ideal and to derive from it his own law, joys and rights – that may well have been considered hitherto to be the most outrageous of human aberrations and idolatry itself; indeed, the few who dared it always felt the need to apologize to themselves, usually as follows: ‘Not I! Not I! But a god through me!’ The wonderful art and power of creating gods – polytheism – was that through which this drive could discharge itself, purify, perfect and ennoble itself; for originally it was a base and undistinguished drive, related to stubbornness, disobedience, and envy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>144</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/144/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/144/</guid>
      <description>Religious wars. – The greatest progress of the masses up till now has been the religious war, for it proves that the mass has begun to treat concepts with respect. Religious wars start only when the finer quarrels among sects have refined common reason so that even the mob becomes subtle and takes trifles seriously, and actually considers it possible that the ‘eternal salvation of the soul’ might hinge on slight differences between concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>145</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/145/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/145/</guid>
      <description>Danger for vegetarians. – A diet consisting primarily of rice leads to the use of opium and narcotics, just as a diet consisting primarily of potatoes leads to the use of liquor. But its subtler effects also include ways of thinking and feeling that work narcotically. This harmonizes with the fact that the promoters of narcotic ways of thinking and feeling, like those Indian gurus, praise precisely a diet that is purely vegetarian and would like to make that a law of the masses: thus they want to call forth and increase a need that they are able to satisfy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>146</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/146/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/146/</guid>
      <description>German hopes. – Let us not forget that names of peoples are usually terms of abuse. The Tartars, for example, are literally ‘the dogs’; that is what the Chinese called them. The ‘Germans’: this originally meant ‘heathen’; that is what the Goths after their conversion named the great mass of their unbaptized kindred tribes, in accordance with their translation of the Septuagint20 in which the heathens were designated with a word that in Greek means ‘the nations’; see Ulfilas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>147</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/147/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/147/</guid>
      <description>Question and answer. – What do savage tribes today take over first of all from the Europeans? Liquor and Christianity, the narcotics of Europe. And from what do they perish most quickly? From European narcotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>148</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/148/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/148/</guid>
      <description>Where reformations arise. – At the time of the great corruption of the Church, the Church in Germany was the least corrupt; that is why the Reformation occurred here, as a sign that even the beginnings of corruption were felt to be intolerable. For relatively speaking, no people has ever been more Christian than the Germans at the time of Luther; their Christian culture was ready to burst into a hundredfold splendour of blossoms – only one more night was needed, but this brought the storm that put an end to everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>149</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/149/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/149/</guid>
      <description>The failure of reformations. – That several attempts to found new Greek religions have failed testifies to the higher culture of the Greeks even in rather early times; it indicates that even early in Greece, there must have been many diverse individuals whose diverse plights could not be disposed of with a single prescription of faith and hope. Pythagoras23 and Plato, perhaps Empedocles24 as well, and the Orphic enthusiasts25 much earlier yet, were out to found new religions; and the former two had souls and talents which were so much those of founders of religions that one cannot wonder enough at their failure; yet all they managed to found were sects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>150</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/150/</guid>
      <description>Towards a critique of saints. – Must one then, in order to have a virtue, want to have it in its most brutal form – the way the Christian saints wanted and needed it, as those who endured life only with the thought that the mere sight of their virtue would destroy the self-esteem of anyone who viewed it? But a virtue with such an effect I call brutal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>151</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/151/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/151/</guid>
      <description>On the origin of religion. – The metaphysical need is not the origin of religion, as Schopenhauer26 has it, but only a late offshoot of it. Under the rule of religious ideas, one has got used to the idea of ‘another world (behind, below, above)’ and feels an unpleasant emptiness and deprivation at the annihilation of religious delusions – and from this feeling grows now ‘another world’, but this time only a metaphysical and not a religious one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>152</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/152/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/152/</guid>
      <description>The greatest change. – The lighting and colours of everything have changed! We no longer fully understand how the ancients experienced what was most familiar and frequent – for example the day and waking. Because the ancients believed in dreams, waking life had a different light. The same goes for the whole of life, illuminated by a light radiated back on it from death and its significance: our ‘death’ is a completely different death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>153</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/153/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/153/</guid>
      <description>*Homo poeta.*27 – ‘I myself, who most single-handedly made this tragedy of tragedies, insofar as it is finished; I, having first tied the knot of morality into existence and drawn it so tight that only a god can loosen it – which is what Horace demands!28 – I myself have now in the fourth act slain all gods, out of morality! What is now to become of the fifth act? From where shall I take the tragic solution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>154</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/154/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/154/</guid>
      <description>Different types of danger in life. – You have no idea what you are experiencing; you run through life as if you were drunk and once in a while fall down a staircase. But thanks to your drunkenness, you don’t break your limbs in the process; your muscles are too slack and your head too dull for you to find the stones of these stairs as hard as the rest of us do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>155</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/155/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/155/</guid>
      <description>What we lack. – We love what is great in nature and have discovered it – because in our heads, great human beings are lacking. It was the other way around for the Greeks; their feeling for nature is different from ours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>156</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/156/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/156/</guid>
      <description>The most influential. – That a human being resists his whole age, stops it at the gate and demands an accounting – that must exercise an influence! Whether he wants to is irrelevant; that he can is what matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>157</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/157/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/157/</guid>
      <description>Mentiri.29 – Watch out! He’s thinking; in a moment he will have a lie ready. This is a stage of culture at which entire peoples have stood. Just consider what the Romans meant by the word mentiri!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>158</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/158/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/158/</guid>
      <description>An uncomfortable trait. – To find all things deep – that is an uncomfortable trait: it makes one constantly strain one’s eyes and in the end always find more than one had wished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>159</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/159/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/159/</guid>
      <description>Every virtue has its age. – Whoever is unyielding these days will often have pangs of conscience because of his candour; for unyieldingness and candour are virtues that belongs to different ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>160</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/160/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/160/</guid>
      <description>Dealing with virtues. – To a virtue, too, one can be undignified and fawning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>161</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/161/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/161/</guid>
      <description>To the lovers of the age. – The ex-priest and the ex-convict constantly make faces: what they want is a face without a past. – But have you ever seen people who know that the future is mirrored in their faces and are so polite to you, you lovers of ‘the age’, that they make a face without a future?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>162</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/162/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/162/</guid>
      <description>Egoism. – Egoism is the perspectival law of feeling according to which what is closest appears large and heavy, while in the distance everything decreases in size and weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>163</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/163/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/163/</guid>
      <description>After a great victory. – The best thing about a great victory is that it takes the fear of defeat out of the victor. ‘Why not also be defeated once?’ he says to himself; ‘I’m rich enough for that now.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>164</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/164/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/164/</guid>
      <description>The seekers of rest. – I recognize the spirits who seek rest by the many dark objects with which they surround themselves: he who wants to sleep makes his room dark or crawls into a cave. – A hint to those who don’t know, but would like to know, what they actually seek most!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>165</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/165/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/165/</guid>
      <description>On the happiness of those who renounce something. – He who thoroughly forgoes something for a long time will, upon accidentally re-encountering it, almost think he has discovered it – and what happiness every discoverer has! Let us be wiser than the snakes who lie too long in the same sunlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>166</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/166/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/166/</guid>
      <description>Always in our company. – Everything that is of my kind, in nature and history, speaks to me, praises me, spurs me on, comforts me – everything else I don’t hear or forget right away. We are always only in our own company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>167</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/167/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/167/</guid>
      <description>Misanthropy and love. – One speaks of being sick of people only when one can no longer digest them and yet still has one’s stomach full of them. Misanthropy is the result of an all-too-greedy love of man and ‘cannibalism’ – but who told you to swallow men like oysters, my Prince Hamlet?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>168</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/168/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/168/</guid>
      <description>About a sick man. – ‘He is doing badly!’ – ‘What’s wrong?’ – ‘He is suffering from the desire to be praised and finds no nourishment for it.’ ‘Unbelievable! The whole world is celebrating him, and pampering him; he is on everyone’s lips.’ – ‘Yes, but he has a bad ear for praise. If a friend praises him, it sounds to him as if the friend is praising himself. If an enemy praises him, it sounds to him as if the enemy wants be praised for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>169</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/169/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/169/</guid>
      <description>Open enemies. – Courage before the enemy is one thing; it does not prevent one from being a coward and indecisive scatterbrain. That is how Napoleon judged ‘the most courageous person’ he knew: Murat.30 Which shows that open enemies are indispensable to some people if they are to rise to their own kind of virtue, manliness, and cheerfulness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>170</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/170/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/170/</guid>
      <description>With the crowd. – So far he is still running with the crowd and singing its praises, but one day he will become its opponent! For he is following it thinking that this will give his laziness full play, and he has not yet discovered that the crowd is not lazy enough for him! That it always pushes ahead! That it allows no one to stand still! – And he so much likes to stand still!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>171</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/171/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/171/</guid>
      <description>Fame. – When the gratitude of many towards one throws away all shame, fame arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>172</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/172/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/172/</guid>
      <description>The spoiler of taste. – A: ‘You are a spoiler of taste – that is what everyone says!’ B: ‘Of course! I spoil for everyone the taste for his own party – and no party forgives that.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>173</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/173/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/173/</guid>
      <description>Being deep and seeming deep. – Those who know they are deep strive for clarity. Those who would like to seem deep to the crowd strive for obscurity. For the crowd takes everything whose ground it cannot see to be deep: it is so timid and so reluctant to go into the water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>174</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/174/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/174/</guid>
      <description>Aside. – Parliamentarianism, i.e. the public permission to choose between five basic political opinions, flatters and wins the favour of all those who like to appear independent and individualistic and would like to fight for their opinions. In the end, however, it is irrelevant whether the herd is commanded to have one opinion or permitted to have five. Whoever deviates from the five public opinions and steps aside will always have the whole herd against him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>175</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/175/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/175/</guid>
      <description>On eloquence. – Who has had the most convincing eloquence so far? The drum roll; and as long as kings and commanders have control over that, they will remain the best orators and rabble rousers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>176</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/176/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/176/</guid>
      <description>Compassion. – Those poor reigning princes! All their rights are now suddenly turning into claims, and all these claims soon begin to sound like presumptions! The moment they merely say ‘We’ or ‘my people’, wicked old Europe starts to smile. Verily, a chief master of ceremonies in the modern world would waste little ceremony on them and might perhaps decree: ‘les souverains rangent aux parvenus.’31</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>177</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/177/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/177/</guid>
      <description>On ‘the educational establishment’. – In Germany, higher men lack one great means of education: the laughter of higher men; for in Germany, these do not laugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>178</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/178/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/178/</guid>
      <description>On moral enlightenment. – One must talk the Germans out of their Mephistopheles, and their Faust, too. They are two moral prejudices against the value of knowledge.32</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>179</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/179/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/179/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts. – Thoughts are the shadows of our sensations – always darker, emptier, simpler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>180</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/180/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/180/</guid>
      <description>The good age for free spirits. – Free spirits take liberties even with science – and for the time being, one also allows them to – as long as the Church is still standing! To that extent they now have their good age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>181</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/181/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/181/</guid>
      <description>Following and leading. – A: ‘Of these two, one will always follow and the other will always lead, wherever fate may take them. And yet the former is superior to the other in virtue and spirit!’ B: ‘And yet? And yet? That was said for the others, not for me, not for us! – Fit secundum regulam.’33</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>182</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/182/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/182/</guid>
      <description>In solitude. – When one lives alone, one neither speaks too loud nor writes too loud, for one fears the hollow echo – the criticism of the nymph Echo. And all voices sound different in solitude!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>183</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/183/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/183/</guid>
      <description>The music of the best future. – I would consider the foremost musician to be the one who knew only the sadness of the deepest happiness, and no other sadness at all; there has never been such a musician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>184</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/184/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/184/</guid>
      <description>Justice. – I’d rather let myself be robbed than be surrounded by scarecrows – that is my taste. And in any case it is a matter of taste – nothing more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>185</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/185/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/185/</guid>
      <description>Poor. – Today he is poor, not because they have taken everything away from him but because he has thrown everything away. What is that to him? He is used to finding things. It is the poor who misunderstand his voluntary poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>186</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/186/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/186/</guid>
      <description>Bad conscience. – Everything he does now is upright and orderly – and still he has a bad conscience. For the extraordinary is his task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>187</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/187/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/187/</guid>
      <description>What is offensive in the presentation. – This artist offends me in the way he presents his ideas, his very good ideas: so broad and emphatic, and with such crude artifices of persuasion, as if he were speaking to a mob. Whenever we devote some time to his art, it is soon as if we were ‘in bad company’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>188</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/188/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/188/</guid>
      <description>Work. – How close work and the worker are now even to the most leisurely among us! The royal courtesy of the words ‘We are all workers!’ would still have been a cynicism and an indecency under the reign of Louis XIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>189</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/189/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/189/</guid>
      <description>The thinker. – He is a thinker: that means he knows how to make things simpler than they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>190</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/190/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/190/</guid>
      <description>Against those who praise. – A: ‘One is praised only by one’s peers.’ B: ‘Yes! And whoever praises you tells you: you are my peer!’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>191</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/191/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/191/</guid>
      <description>Against many a defence. – The most perfidious way of damaging a cause is deliberately to defend it with faulty arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>192</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/192/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/192/</guid>
      <description>The good-natured. – What distinguishes those good-natured people whose faces radiate good will from the rest? They feel well in the presence of another person and quickly fall in love with him; consequently they wish him well, and their first judgement is: ‘I like him.’ In such people there is the following succession: the wish to appropriate (they do not scruple much over the worth of the other person), quick appropriation, delight in possession, and action for the benefit of the person possessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>193</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/193/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/193/</guid>
      <description>Kant’s joke. – Kant wanted to prove, in a way that would dumbfound the whole world, that the whole world was right: that was the secret joke of this soul. He wrote against the scholars in favour of popular prejudice, but for scholars and not for the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>194</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/194/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/194/</guid>
      <description>The ‘openhearted’ one. – That person probably always acts according to secret reasons, for he always has communicable reasons on his tongue and virtually in his open hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>195</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/195/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/195/</guid>
      <description>Laughable. – Look! Look! He is running away from people, but they follow him because he is running ahead of them – that is how much they are a herd!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>196</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/196/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/196/</guid>
      <description>Limits of our sense of hearing. – One hears only those questions to which one is able to find an answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>197</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/197/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/197/</guid>
      <description>Better be careful! – There is nothing we like so much to impart to others as the seal of secrecy – along with what is under it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>198</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/198/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/198/</guid>
      <description>Chagrin of the proud one. – The proud man feels chagrined even by those who bring him forward: he gives the horse of his carriage the evil eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>199</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/199/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/199/</guid>
      <description>Generosity. – With the rich, generosity is often just a type of shyness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>200</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/200/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/200/</guid>
      <description>Laughter. – Laughter means: to gloat, but with a good conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>201</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/201/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/201/</guid>
      <description>Applause. – In applause there is always a kind of noise – even in the applause we give ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>202</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/202/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/202/</guid>
      <description>A squanderer. – As yet he does not have that poverty of the rich man who has already counted his entire treasure once – he squanders his spirit with the unreason of a squandering nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>203</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/203/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/203/</guid>
      <description>Hic niger est.34 – Usually he has no thought – but on rare occasions bad thoughts come to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>204</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/204/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/204/</guid>
      <description>Beggars and courtesy. – ‘One isn’t being impolite if one uses a stone to knock on a door which lacks a doorbell’: that is how beggars think, and everyone who is suffering some kind of distress, but no one thinks they are right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>205</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/205/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/205/</guid>
      <description>Need. – Need is taken to be the cause why something came to be; in reality, it is often merely an effect of what has come to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>206</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/206/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/206/</guid>
      <description>When it rains. – It is raining, and I think of the poor who now huddle together with their many troubles and without any practice at concealing them: each is ready to hurt the other and to make for himself a pitiful kind of pleasure even when the weather is bad. That and that alone is the poverty of the poor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>207</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/207/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/207/</guid>
      <description>The envious one. – He is envious – let’s hope he won’t have any children; he would envy them because he can no longer be a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>208</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/208/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/208/</guid>
      <description>Great man! – From the fact that someone is a ‘great man’ one cannot infer that he is a man; he may be just a boy, or a chameleon of all stages of life, or a bewitched little woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>209</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/209/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/209/</guid>
      <description>A way of asking for reasons. – There is a way of asking us for our reasons that not only makes us forget our best reasons but also awakens in us a defiance and resistance towards reasons in general – a very stultifying mode of asking and a trick used by tyrannical people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>210</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/210/</guid>
      <description>Moderation in diligence. – One should not try to surpass one’s father in diligence; that makes one sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>211</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/211/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/211/</guid>
      <description>Secret enemies. – To be able to afford a secret enemy – that is a luxury for which the morality even of elevated spirits is usually not rich enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>212</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/212/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/212/</guid>
      <description>Not to let oneself be deceived. – His spirit has bad manners, is hasty and always stutters out of impatience; hence one hardly recognizes how much stamina and robustness the soul possesses in which this spirit dwells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>213</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/213/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/213/</guid>
      <description>The road to happiness. – A wise man asked a fool what the road to happiness is. The latter replied without delay, like someone being asked the way to the nearest town: ‘Admire yourself and live on the street!’ ‘Stop,’ replied the sage, ‘you are asking too much; it is quite enough to admire oneself!’ The fool countered: ‘But how can one constantly admire without constantly feeling contempt?’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>214</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/214/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/214/</guid>
      <description>Faith makes blessed. – Virtue gives happiness and a type of blessedness only to those who have not lost faith in their virtue – not to those subtler souls whose virtue consists of a deep mistrust of themselves and of all virtue. So in the end, here, too, ‘faith makes blessed’35 – and, mind you, not virtue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>215</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/215/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/215/</guid>
      <description>Ideal and material. – You envisage a noble ideal, but are you such a noble stone that such a divine image could be fashioned out of you? And anyway – isn’t all your work a barbarous sculpting? A blasphemy against your ideal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>216</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/216/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/216/</guid>
      <description>Danger in the voice. – With a very loud voice in one’s throat one is almost incapable of thinking subtle things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>217</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/217/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/217/</guid>
      <description>Cause and effect. – Before the effect one believes in causes different from those one believes in after the effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>218</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/218/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/218/</guid>
      <description>My antipathy. – I do not love people who have to explode like bombs in order to have any effect whatsoever and in whose presence one is always in danger of suddenly losing one’s hearing – or more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>219</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/219/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/219/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of punishment. – The purpose of punishment is to improve the one who punishes; that is the last resort of the apologists for punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>220</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/220/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/220/</guid>
      <description>Sacrifice. – The sacrificial animal thinks differently about sacrifice than the spectator, but one has never let it have its say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>221</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/221/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/221/</guid>
      <description>Forbearance. – Fathers and sons have much more forbearance for each other than mothers and daughters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>222</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/222/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/222/</guid>
      <description>Poet and liar. – The poet sees in the liar a foster brother (Milchbruder) whose milk he has drunk up; that is why the latter has remained stunted and miserable and has not even got as far as having a good conscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>223</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/223/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/223/</guid>
      <description>Vicariousness of the senses. – ‘Our eyes are also intended for hearing’, said the old father confessor who had gone deaf, ‘and among the blind he is king who has the longest ears.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>224</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/224/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/224/</guid>
      <description>Animals’ criticism. – I fear that the animals see man as a being like them who in a most dangerous manner has lost his animal common sense – as the insane animal, the laughing animal, the weeping animal, the miserable animal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>225</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/225/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/225/</guid>
      <description>The natural. – ‘Evil has always had great effects in its favour! And nature is evil! Let us therefore be natural!’ That is the secret reasoning of the great effect-artists of humanity, who have all too often been considered great human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>226</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/226/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/226/</guid>
      <description>The distrustful and style. – We say the strongest things simply, provided that we are among people who believe in our strength – such an environment breeds ‘simplicity of style’. The distrustful speak emphatically; the distrustful make emphatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>227</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/227/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/227/</guid>
      <description>Bad inference; bad shot. – He cannot control himself; from that, a woman infers that it would be easy to control him and casts her net for him – the poor woman who will shortly be his slave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>228</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/228/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/228/</guid>
      <description>Against mediators. – He who wants to mediate between two resolute thinkers shows that he is mediocre: he has no eye for what is unique; seeing things as similar and making things the same is the sign of weak eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>229</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/229/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/229/</guid>
      <description>Obstinacy and faithfulness. – From defiance he clings to something he has come to see through, but he calls it ‘faithfulness’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>230</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/230/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/230/</guid>
      <description>Lack of silence. – His whole being fails to persuade – that is because he has never remained silent about any of his good deeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>231</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/231/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/231/</guid>
      <description>The ‘thorough’. – Those who are slow to know think that slowness is an aspect of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>232</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/232/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/232/</guid>
      <description>Dreaming. – Either one does not dream, or does so interestingly. One should learn to spend one’s waking life in the same way: not at all, or interestingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>233</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/233/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/233/</guid>
      <description>The most dangerous point of view. – What I now do or omit is as important for everything that is to come as the greatest event of the past: seen from this tremendous perspective, from that of their effects, all actions appear equally great and small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>234</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/234/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/234/</guid>
      <description>Words of comfort for a musician. – ‘Your life does not reach men’s ears; to them you live a mute life, and all the subtlety of melody, all tender resolution about following or leading, remain hidden from them. It is true: you are not coming down a main street with regimental music, but that does not give these good people the right to say your way of life lacks music. He who has ears to hear, let him hear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>235</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/235/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/235/</guid>
      <description>Spirit and character. – Some reach their peak as characters, but their spirit is not adequate for this height, while with others it is the other way around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>236</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/236/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/236/</guid>
      <description>In order to move the crowd. – Must not he who wants to move the crowd be an actor playing the role of himself? Must he not first translate himself into the grotesquely obvious and present his entire person and cause in this coarsened and simplified version?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>237</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/237/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/237/</guid>
      <description>The polite one. – ‘He is so polite!’ – Yes, he always carries a cake for Cerberus36 and is so timid that he takes everyone for Cerberus, even you and me; that is his ‘politeness’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>238</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/238/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/238/</guid>
      <description>Without envy. – He is quite without envy, but that has no merit because he wants to conquer a country that no one has yet possessed and hardly anyone has ever seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>239</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/239/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/239/</guid>
      <description>The joyless one. – One single joyless person is enough to create constant sullenness and dark skies for a an entire household, and only a miracle can cause that one person to be lacking! Happiness is not nearly as contagious a disease – why is that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>240</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/240/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/240/</guid>
      <description>At the sea. – I wouldn’t build a house for myself (and it is part of my good fortune not to be a home-owner!). But if I had to, I would, like some Romans, build it right into the sea – I certainly would like to share a few secrets with this beautiful monster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>241</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/241/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/241/</guid>
      <description>Work and artist. – This artist is ambitious, nothing more: ultimately his work is just a magnifying glass that he offers everyone who looks his way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>242</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/242/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/242/</guid>
      <description>Suum cuique?37 – However great my greed for knowledge may be, I cannot take anything else out of things than what already belongs to me – what belongs to others remains behind. How is it possible for a human being to be a thief or a robber!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>243</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/243/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/243/</guid>
      <description>Origin of ‘good’ and ‘bad’. – An improvement is invented only by someone who is able to feel ‘this is not good’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>244</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/244/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/244/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts and words. – Even one’s thoughts one cannot entirely reproduce in words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>245</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/245/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/245/</guid>
      <description>Praise by choice. – The artist chooses his subjects; that is his way of praising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>246</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/246/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/246/</guid>
      <description>Mathematics. – Let us introduce the subtlety and rigour of mathematics into all sciences to the extent to which that is at all possible; not in the belief that we will come to know things this way, but in order to ascertain our human relation to things. Mathematics is only the means to general and final knowledge of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>247</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/247/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/247/</guid>
      <description>Habit. – Every habit makes our hand more witty and our wit less handy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>248</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/248/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/248/</guid>
      <description>Books. – What good is a book that does not even carry us beyond all books?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>249</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/249/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/249/</guid>
      <description>The sigh of the one who comes to know. – ‘Oh, my greed! In this soul there dwells no selflessness but rather an all-desiring self that would like, as it were, to see with the eyes and seize with the hands of many individuals – a self that would like to bring back the entire past, that wants to lose nothing it could possibly possess! Oh, this flame of my greed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>250</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/250/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/250/</guid>
      <description>Guilt. – Although the shrewdest judges of the witches and even the witches themselves were convinced of the guilt of witchcraft, this guilt still did not exist. This is true of all guilt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>251</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/251/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/251/</guid>
      <description>Misunderstood sufferers. – Great natures suffer differently from what their admirers imagine: they suffer most severely from the ignoble, petty agitations of some evil moments – in short, from their doubts about their own greatness – and not from the sacrifices and martyrdoms that their task demands from them. As long as Prometheus has pity for men and sacrifices himself for them, he is happy and great; but when he is envious of Zeus and the homage paid to him by mortals, then he suffers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>252</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/252/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/252/</guid>
      <description>Better in debt. – ‘Better to remain in debt than to pay with a coin that does not bear our image!’ says our sovereignty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>253</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/253/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/253/</guid>
      <description>Always at home. – One day we reach our goal – and now we point with pride to the long journeys we took to reach it. In truth we did not notice we were travelling. But we got so far because at each point we believed we were at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>254</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/254/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/254/</guid>
      <description>Against embarrassment. – Whoever is always deeply occupied is beyond all embarrassment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>255</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/255/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/255/</guid>
      <description>Imitators. – A: ‘What? You want no imitators?’ B: ‘I don’t want people to imitate me; I want everyone to set his own example, which is what I do.’ A: ‘So –?’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>256</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/256/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/256/</guid>
      <description>Skinnedness. – All people of depth find happiness in being for once like flying fish, playing on the outermost crests of waves; what they consider best in things is that they have a surface: their skinnedness – sit venia verbo.38</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>257</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/257/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/257/</guid>
      <description>From experience. – Some do not know how rich they are until they experience what kinds of rich people will steal from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>258</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/258/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/258/</guid>
      <description>Those who deny chance. – No victor believes in chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>259</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/259/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/259/</guid>
      <description>From paradise. – ‘Good and evil are the prejudices of God’ – said the snake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>260</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/260/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/260/</guid>
      <description>One times one. – One is always wrong; but with two, truth begins. – One cannot prove his case, but two are already irrefutable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>261</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/261/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/261/</guid>
      <description>Originality. – What is originality? To see something that still has no name; that still cannot be named even though it is lying right before everyone’s eyes. The way people usually are, it takes a name to make something visible at all. – Those with originality have usually been the name-givers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>262</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/262/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/262/</guid>
      <description>Sub specie aeterni.39 – A: ‘You are moving ever faster from the living: soon they will strike you out of their lists!’ – B: ‘That is the only way to participate in the privilege of the dead.’ – A: ‘What privilege?’ – B: ‘No longer to die.’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>263</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/263/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/263/</guid>
      <description>Without vanity. – When we are in love we want our defects to remain hidden – not from vanity but so the loved one won’t suffer. Yes, the lover would like to be godlike – also not from vanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>264</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/264/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/264/</guid>
      <description>What we do. – What we do is never understood but always merely praised and reproached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>265</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/265/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/265/</guid>
      <description>Ultimate doubt. – What, then, are man’s truths ultimately? – They are the irrefutable errors of man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>266</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/266/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/266/</guid>
      <description>Where cruelty is needed. – He who has greatness is cruel to his virtues and secondary considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>267</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/267/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/267/</guid>
      <description>With a great goal. – With a great goal one is superior even to justice, not only to one’s deeds and judges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>268</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/268/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/268/</guid>
      <description>What makes one heroic? – To approach at the same time one’s highest suffering and one’s highest hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>269</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/269/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/269/</guid>
      <description>What do you believe in? – In this: that the weight of all things must be determined anew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>270</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/270/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/270/</guid>
      <description>What does your conscience say? – ‘You should become who you are.’40</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>271</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/271/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/271/</guid>
      <description>Where lie your greatest dangers? – In compassion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>272</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/272/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/272/</guid>
      <description>What do you love in others? – My hopes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>273</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/273/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/273/</guid>
      <description>Whom do you call bad? – He who always wants to put people to shame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>274</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/274/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/274/</guid>
      <description>What is most human to you? – To spare someone shame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>275</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/275/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/3_Book_Three/275/</guid>
      <description>What is the seal of having become free’? – No longer to be ashamed before oneself.
1 Group of philosophers in the early fifth century BC who argued that the world of change was a mere appearance of an underlying unchanging being
2 The German word ‘Recht’ is usually ambiguous, meaning both ‘right’ and ‘law’. In this case it seems best to render it as ‘justice’.
3 Ariston lived in the third century BC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
