<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;08 IMMORTALS on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;08 IMMORTALS on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Siddhas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/01_Siddhas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/01_Siddhas/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The universe is endless and beginningless.&amp;rdquo; Vimalananda was in a mood to talk, and plenty of time lay before us. “If you are sincere and work hard you will eventually reach the state of continual awareness that you are the Universal Soul, the One, the Atman or Brahman. Then you can truthfully say to yourself, &amp;lsquo;Aham Brahmasmi; I am Brahman.&amp;rsquo; Our mortal consciousness has three normal states: waking, dream, and deep sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Rishis, Munis, Naths and Siddhas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/02_Rishis_Munis_Naths_and_Siddhas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/02_Rishis_Munis_Naths_and_Siddhas/</guid>
      <description>After pausing to light a cigarette, Vimalananda continued.
“To become a Siddha is wonderful-marvelous&amp;ndash;but it is not the ulti mate. If your Kundalini should ever reach the Sahasrara you will see so many things that you will be amazed. You will see hundreds and hundreds of flow ers of all colors. Each of those flowers is a shakti, and if you pluck one of them you will get that shakti, which will keep you on the periphery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Notable Siddhas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/03_Notable_Siddhas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/03_Notable_Siddhas/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;To meet a Nath, Muni or Rishi, or one of the Supreme Shaktis, is almost impossible. But you may be able to meet Siddhas. I was very fortunate to have met Telang Swami (see Aghora), who was a great Siddha. When I was in
12121
IMMORTALS
the Himalayas I met Babaji, the Siddha who Yogananda talks about. Babaji is a good Siddha, no doubt, but his sister is even better than he is!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Rishis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/04_Rishis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/04_Rishis/</guid>
      <description>Vimalananda lit yet another cigarette. &amp;ldquo;Nothing is ever lost in the universe. Even things which happened mil lions of years ago can still be known, because their sound still exists. Sound, which is vibration, a series of waves, can be transmitted in many ways. Light can carry sound; even modern science has proved this. Humans usually perceive sound via molecules of air that vibrate; in light something else vibrates, but sound is there within light all the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/05_Time_and_Space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/05_Time_and_Space/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is a problem only because you lack patience. If you decide that locat ing a Rishi is the thing you want most to do you will set about doing it, no matter how many lifetimes it may take. It is only a matter of time, after all.
“Being immortal the Rishis are not subject to time as we know it. They have gone beyond the reach of Mahakala, the God of Death, whose name is Time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Anasuya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/06_Anasuya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/06_Anasuya/</guid>
      <description>i
&amp;ldquo;It is very beautiful.”
&amp;ldquo;A Rishi&amp;rsquo;s wife is an amazing being in her own right. What about Anasuya, the wife of the Rishi Atri? Her very name means &amp;lsquo;absence of envy.&amp;rsquo; What more could one want in a wife? And just as she was without envy, everyone was envious of her. Even Lakshmi, Sarasvati and Parvati, the wives of Vishnu, Brahma and Shiva, became envious of her, and one day they got together and decided to tell their husbands to go and disturb her penance so she would not stand out as the example of what a wife should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Avataras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/07_Avataras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/08_IMMORTALS/07_Avataras/</guid>
      <description>“Dattatreya is unique. But then, his father was a Rishi. Each Rishi offers his own experience to the world by sending down his essence to be bom as a prophet or a saint, to guide and teach. When things on Earth come to such a pass that the continued existence of the Rishis&amp;rsquo; Lila seems threat ened, a Rishi will send down an emanation of himself to guide the errant sheep back to the fold, as Jesus tried to do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
