<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cricket on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cricket on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The sub-continental stirrings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-12-18_the-sub-continental-stirrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-12-18_the-sub-continental-stirrings/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
We had earlier commented how the Trojan horse, whom we used to call Chappal (slipper) in our days of youth was working his wonders with the Indian army. We had speculated that he was specifically an agent of the roguish pirate chief Ponting to do away with his main dangers before the invasion of the subcontinent. We have now got some intelligence as to how the Indian ants invited the parasitoid wasp Greg “Chappal” into their nest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trojan horse?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-11-12_the-trojan-horse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-11-12_the-trojan-horse/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
With the fall of general Wright, the Hindu armies employed a new trainer in the form of the roguish chief from Southern Saxony, Chappell. we have long known Chappell to be an abrasive character, who has always had his own quirks. He quickly got into a conflict with the prince of Vanga and the brave Andhra grenadier from Vangipura. We believe that the Anglo-Saxon is a Trojan horse sent by the king of the Southern Whites to ruin the Hindu armies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The clash of Saxons</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-08-28_the-clash-of-saxons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2005-08-28_the-clash-of-saxons/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The great leader of the Southern Saxon, Pirate king Slit-Eyes had died in the battle with the Hindus during their invasion of the southern continent. Slit-Eyes was succeeded by pirate Ponting, who was ably supported by the old guard of the Slit-Eyes empire, such as Gen. Hayden, bombardier McGrath, raider-in-chief Warnie, captains Langer and Gilchrist, Bishop Martyn and other saboteurs, Clarke, Gillespie and Lee. The Southern Saxons in the heydays of Slit-Eyes and Pirate Emperor Border, had engaged in many raiding operations on the Saxon mainland, and had fought many epic battle even as the pirates of the Caribbeans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mother of all battles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2003-12-16_the-mother-of-all-battles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/MT/cricket/2003-12-16_the-mother-of-all-battles/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
The ruffians of Southern Saxony had always held the Indian armies in contempt. In one of the greatest battles of all times the princes of the Andhra and the Karnata country had destroyed the Saxon pride that had swelled in the great invasion of India in the year of 2001 under Emperor of all Saxony, Slit-Eyes+++(=nAsser Hussain?)+++. In the battle of Chennai the prince of Mumbai had put to sword the Southern Saxon army.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
