<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Misc on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Misc on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chaturagiry Agastya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/chaturagiry-Agastya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/chaturagiry-Agastya/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Chaturagiri: The Abode of Siddhas
Chaturagiri: The Abode of Siddhas
It was past mid-day when I reached the small temple dedicated to the guardian deity of the hills. He is Karuppusamy sporting a long moustache, his stretched right hand holding a sword and body decked with ornaments. The journey was tiring and I had trekked over five hours from the base camp. A half an hour climb lay ahead to the top of the hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craig Macmillan celebration</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/craig-macmillan-celebration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/craig-macmillan-celebration/</guid>
      <description>What do you see? A man celebrating, right? That man, for those who don’t know, is New Zealand’s Craig McMillan. So, what’s McMillan celebrating? A century. That’s nice, right? A century that came off 67 balls. Gets better? Let me make it even better. A century off 67 balls against arch-rivals Australia in a chase of 347 when his team was down at 41/4 when he walked in. Sounds almost like some script of a movie, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erase out of existance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/erase-out-of-existance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/erase-out-of-existance/</guid>
      <description>(Source: https://threader.app/thread/1462620572140007428)
I was 20 years old when I was sent to erase a man from existence and became haunted by him. I was going to college in Texas at the time and a group of us were contacted about a service project. The State needed a handful of young volunteers over the course of a Sunday afternoon and I was one of about ten that agreed to help.We were asked to go to the home of an elderly gentleman that had recently died and help sort his belongings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>puNya for money</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/puNya_for_money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/puNya_for_money/</guid>
      <description>About a hundred years ago, a distant relative of Rāḻḻapalli Ananthakrishna Sarma had once gone on a pilgrimage to Kāśī and other places. When he was in Mathura or in some other place, he had completely spent all his money. It was not easy in those times to procure money by writing a letter back home.
With no other option, he went to one of the pawn-broker shops and requested the lender, “I need some money now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randy Pausch - Last lecture</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/randy-pausch_last-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/randy-pausch_last-lecture/</guid>
      <description>विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्) Randy Pausch Last Lecture: Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams Transcript
Randy Pausch
Carnegie Mellon Professor Randy Pausch’s last lecture titled “Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams” was delivered on September 18, 2007 in a packed McConomy Auditorium at the CMU, where he talked on his childhood dreams, enabling the dreams of others and some lessons learned in his journey of life. Below is the full transcript of the lecture by Randy…</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
