<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;07 Preface to the second edition on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;07 Preface to the second edition on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/1/</guid>
      <description>This book might need more than one preface; and in the end there would still be room for doubting whether someone who has not experienced something similar could, by means of prefaces, be brought closer to the experiences of this book. It seems to be written in the language of the wind that brings a thaw: it contains high spirits, unrest, contradiction, and April weather, so that one is constantly reminded of winter’s nearness as well as of the triumph over winter that is coming, must come, perhaps has already come&amp;hellip;Gratitude flows forth incessantly, as if that which was most unexpected had just happened – the gratitude of a convalescent – for recovery was what was most unexpected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/2/</guid>
      <description>But let us leave Mr. Nietzsche: what is it to us that Mr Nietzsche has got well again?&amp;hellip;A psychologist knows few questions as attractive as that concerning the relation between health and philosophy; and should he himself become ill, he will bring all of his scientific curiosity into the illness. For assuming that one is a person, one necessarily also has the philosophy of that person; but here there is a considerable difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/3/</guid>
      <description>– One might guess that I do not want to take my leave ungratefully from that time of severe illness whose profits I have not yet exhausted even today: I am well aware of the advantages that my erratic health gives me over all burly minds. A philosopher who has passed through many kinds of health, and keeps passing through them again and again, has passed through an equal number of philosophies; he simply cannot but translate his state every time into the most spiritual form and distance – this art of transfiguration just is philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/0/07_Preface_to_the_second_edition/4/</guid>
      <description>Finally, lest what is most important remain unsaid: from such abysses, from such severe illness, also from the illness of severe suspicion, one returns newborn, having shed one’s skin, more ticklish and malicious, with a more delicate taste for joy, with a more tender tongue for all good things, with merrier senses, joyful with a more dangerous second innocence, more childlike, and at the same time a hundred times subtler than one had ever been before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
