<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Misc on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Misc on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ashish_to_Adil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/Ashish_to_Adil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/Ashish_to_Adil/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Men are targets of Love J_had as much as women are! A colleague’s younger brother worked in fashion industry. Let’s call him Ashish. He worked with a European brand making denim. There he met a young woman- let’s call her Shaheen.
Shaheen came across as liberal Mz. Loved Gujarati food which Ashish’s baa sent for him. Slowly she found place in his circle. They were seen together. The family was not conservative &amp;amp; thought this was merely a casual liking, they were sure Ashish would not go beyond friendship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On rAmakRShNa&#39;s &#39;tantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/on_rAmakRShNa-tantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/on_rAmakRShNa-tantra/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Understanding Sadhana through the Life of Sri Ramakrishna: The Experience of God Realization through Tantric Sadhana — IV
PRAVRAJIKA VIVEKAPRANA
Sri Ramakrishna had moved on to the level of Vishishtha Advaita, where he got a little bit of help from gurus. The first guru was Bhairavi Brahmani.
Sri Ramakrishna, by his own desire to realize the various forms of God, practised the well-known ways of reaching out to the realization of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNAnubandha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/RNAnubandha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/RNAnubandha/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Consequences of bad karma, real life example of account balance, the reasons for accepting the kārmika backfire. Ṛṇānubandhana in jyotiśa, how it works
Abduction In 2009, my cousin who was a senior gynaecologist was attending my wife. My wife delivered a healthy girl over 4 kg. However, the paediatrician over there just told us that my child is suffering from acute pneumonia and she needs to be operated immediately (There was no symptoms and my sister countered him but she cannot to do anything as he was the paediatrician).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sikh hindu muslim marriage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/sikh-hindu-muslim-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/sikh-hindu-muslim-marriage/</guid>
      <description>I think I am the most appropriate women to answer this as I am a Sikh women married to a Muslim man for last 28 yrs in the state of Madhya Pradesh. We got married in year 1990. For understandable reasons you can excuse me for not coming up with my real name as being a mother of one daughter and son at this age I would like to keep my identity intact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>svembu-child-autism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/svembu-child-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/svembu-child-autism/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Autism fight With vicious personal attacks and slander on my character, it is time for me to respond. This is a deeply painful personal thread. My personal life, in contrast to my business life, has been a long tragedy. Autism destroyed our lives and left me suicidally depressed.
My wife Pramila and I were in this fight against autism for over 15 years. She is a super mom and her passionate cause is curing our son of autism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinay community consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/vinay-community-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/misc/vinay-community-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>A story
on
Community
Consciousness
A f i c t i o n s t o r y b a s e d on f a c t s Version-1.0 (alpha)
Paripoornam 🌕🪷☀- A Self Sustainable Community in India based on Natural Living, Natural Farming, Mud homes &amp;amp; Natural Learning. Authentic Alternative School with academics mapped to real world life skills and activities, and health giving education because teachers inner work is such that healing and therapy is part of the curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
