<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AshIsha-dhAra on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AshIsha-dhAra on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 White pill</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/2021_white-pill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/2021_white-pill/</guid>
      <description>A rare random white pill.
At this point, Hindu resurgence is approaching a point of inflection. There was one such turning point some years back, which significantly shifted the Overton window away from the inane secularist gibberish that followed from the state sponsored indoctrination also called Indian schooling. The indoctrination went on unchecked in the pre-internet era. With the coming of the internet, it took just a decade for truth to prevail on the emotional plane and a large number of people outgrew their conditioning and fear to start speaking freely about things that had oppressed them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Hindu situation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/hindu-situation-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/hindu-situation-2022/</guid>
      <description>The recent spate of Hindu k!11!ngs in Kashmir is not surprising, at least to those who place the truth above loyalty to strangers in power. For everyone else it is yet another ineffective reality check that does not even generate online outrage any longer. But why are H so obstinately immune to reality? Here are five systemic reasons, in no particular order but all organically linked and reinforcing each other to form a vicious cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economy vs Justice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/economy_vs_justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/economy_vs_justice/</guid>
      <description>I had the great misfortune of being a witness in an open and shut civil suit in a Delhi court. The case was filed in Apr 2019 and the judge had it entirely figured out in the first two hearings which were done by June. It&amp;rsquo;s been over 2 years since. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count of the number of hearings now &amp;amp; there is absolutely zero progress. Luckily the complainant can afford to pay the lawyer just for marking attendance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jAti-varNa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/jAti-varNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/jAti-varNa/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Although intrinsically related, Jaati and Varna can be considered separate for the purpose of grasping the concepts. Even historically, Varna was not always discernible for there is no empirical laboratory test to determine the same. When the British started categorising Hindu communities into castes, they frequently ran into people who knew their jaati but didn&amp;rsquo;t even know what to make of the term &amp;lsquo;Varna&amp;rsquo;. That does not mean that Varna is expendable but quite simply that it does not lend itself to reductionist hot takes by politicians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>karmayogi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/karmayogi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/karmayogi/</guid>
      <description>[Replug from April 2018] Adi Shankaracharya The Wikipedia entry for Adi Shankara introduces him as &amp;ldquo;an early 8th century Indian philosopher and theologian who consolidated the doctrine of Advaita Vedanta&amp;rdquo;. It is reflective of the modern understanding of his life and achievements. Therefore, it is patently untrue.
The 8th century claim has, of course, been contested by the very mathas he established but there are even more significant things that would be called &amp;lsquo;problematic&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kAshInAtha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/kAshInAtha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/kAshInAtha/</guid>
      <description>That Kashmir earned for itself the title, &amp;lsquo;Rishi-waer&amp;rsquo; or the garden of Rishis, is not a matter of chance or romantic speculation. If you were born in Kashmir as a Hindu, you would have to be exceedingly obtuse to miss this glaring everyday fact of life. The valley was indeed a powerhouse that seemed to attract high-voltage specimens of our species. They were called &amp;ldquo;maet&amp;rdquo; in plural, crazy literally or &amp;ldquo;mastanas&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KP Idiot Celebs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/kp-idiot-celebs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/kp-idiot-celebs/</guid>
      <description>Two things happened today. First, I read about the statements on Kashmir made by a couple of Kashmiri Pandit ladies, Nitasha Kaul and Aarti Tikoo Singh (incidentally a darling of the Raitawing), at the US House Foreign Affairs Committee hearing. I quote from the written statement submitted by the latter: &amp;ldquo;What the foot-soldiers of the Pakistani military and ISI (Inter-Services Intelligence) have done to ordinary Kashmiri Muslims in the last 30 years, pales in comparison to the human rights violations committed by the Indian state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Male degradation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/male-degradation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/male-degradation/</guid>
      <description>Allowing the government to take care of us is always about the tacit consent to removing our skin from the game, superficially akin to outsourcing the disagreeable or difficult tasks to experts but closer to giving up personal and communal responsibility. There is a line to be drawn somewhere but apparently we ran out of ink long back. It is a vicious circle that we descended into at the time of independence, or maybe even before that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaning vs power</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/meaning_vs_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/meaning_vs_power/</guid>
      <description>In a recent conversation with a friend on the rising threat associated with speaking your mind in a typical American workplace, I remarked that the abandonment of the sacred realm in modern society has made people emotionally fragile and socially handicapped. In healthy traditional societies, the sacred belongs to the Gods. In societies that are falling apart, the idea of a jealous grandfather in the sky and his sidekick occupies that space but still manages to keep insanity at bay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pashubali learnings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/pashubali-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/pashubali-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Learnings from the reactions to pashubali from the krantikaris of modern India:
There is little to differentiate a rootless liberal from a political Hindu when it comes to their views on Dharma. Modern Hindus lack a basic understanding of fundamental aspects/concepts of Dharma like sampradAya, adhikAra, shAstra, pramAna etc. Respect for figures of authority like the revered AchAryas is completely missing and so is an awareness, much less the appreciation, of the rich dialectical tradition they have unfortunately inherited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion of Awe</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/religion_of_awe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/religion_of_awe/</guid>
      <description>A hundred thousand years ago, we were just noisy apes halfway up the forest food chain. Then something happened. We gave up the insistence on close blood ties to form the bonds of trust. We learnt the art of large-scale collaboration. Sapiens began to dominate the planet and raced to the top of the pyramid. This rush to the top, attributable entirely to a large number of homosapiens working towards common objectives was made possible by the art of storytelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VHP &amp; bajrang dal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/vhp_bajrang-dal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/AshIsh-dhAr/vhp_bajrang-dal/</guid>
      <description>Too many people suddenly feeling nostalgic about Bajrang Dal and VHP. They are lamenting that they are no longer a patch on what they used to be. Well, they were cut down to size by the bigshots as soon as they started smelling power in the 90s. The thing is the bigshots were uncomfortable with their existence because the so-called goons were no longer politically useful to them and only embarrassed them in the media, 5-star conferences, and lit fests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
