<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Left hand on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Left hand on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/00/</guid>
      <description>VIMALANANDA’S DEDICATION FOR THIS BOOK Dedicated to One who is the source of life
The Dynamic Cosmic Energy which pervades
the entire universe perennially
The fountainhead of supreme joy, divinity, and magnanimity:
Portrait of Vimalananda
(taken from a photograph and drawn by Dr. Vasant D. Lad.)
My Mother Tara Vimalananda, the subject of this book, designed the cover and dictated to the author the following regarding its symbolic meaning:
“Ghora is darkness, the darkness of ignorance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 MA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/01_MA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/01_MA/</guid>
      <description>To be a guru you have to say, “I know and I can teach you.” But if I say that, well, I’m finished. I can never learn anything else. I have shut myself off from anything new. If I remain a student all my life, though, I will always be ready to learn new things.
I never call any of the people who come to me for spiritual guidance “disciples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 SHAKTI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/02_SHAKTI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/02_SHAKTI/</guid>
      <description>When I’m disgusted, fed up with the world, I always turn to my Mother. She comes to me in any form I request, and we play that way. Sometimes She comes as my Mother, sometimes as my wife, sometimes as my child. She’s always with me; She’ll never go away. Long ago we promised each other to stay together always. If She ever leaves me I will not live even an instant longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 SHIVA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/03_SHIVA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/03_SHIVA/</guid>
      <description>The world considers You inauspicious, O Destroyer of Lust who plays in the smashan smeared with the ash from funeral pyres, wearing a necklace of human skulls, with ghouls for comrades. But for those who remember You with devotion, O Bestower of Boons, You are supremely auspicious. (Shiva Mahimna Stotra, 24)
MAHAKALA
One day I said to Smashan Tara, “You are my Ma, my Mother, but who is my Father?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 RNANUBANDHANA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/04_RNANUBANDHANA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/04_RNANUBANDHANA/</guid>
      <description>Punarapi jananam, punarapi maranam, punarapi matrdareshayanam: Birth and death and living in a womb, over and over and over again.
THE PRIMAL DEBT
What is the purpose of being born? To recognize yourself, to realize that you are neither the body nor the mind but rather the Eternal Soul which is the Ultimate Unity — call it Atma, Parampurusha, Brahman, or what you like.
How is one born into the world, though?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 MENTORS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/05_MENTORS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/05_MENTORS/</guid>
      <description>Nature is very kind to me; in fact, as my friend Faram used to say, Nature is cockeyed to me. And that is because of my mentors. My mentors were very good. That’s all I can say; my mentors were very good. Maybe it’s true I was meant by Nature to succeed at all my sadhanas, but my mentors triggered me up and made me succeed. They were too good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 AGHORA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/06_AGHORA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/06_AGHORA/</guid>
      <description>When I look at someone I don’t see them as they are now; I see them as they will be. Then I can try to change them if there is something in them I think I can change. If I love skin and bones how will I be able to help them? Skin and bones will only decay, but the individual will continue to exist even after death. That is why I can say that I love people not for their present value but for their future value; not for what they are but for what they will become, or for what they have the potential to become.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 SPIRITS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/07_SPIRITS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/07_SPIRITS/</guid>
      <description>If a four-year-old boy were to sit on top of his dead grandmother, pick up his father’s japamala and begin to do japa, what sort of boy would you say he is? You would have to say he was born to do Smashan Sadhana. I have seen a boy who did that. Why, even I, when I was a child, used to build toy funeral pyres out of twigs and matchsticks; it’s an inborn tendency in someone who is meant to be an Aghori.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 AVISHKARA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/08_AVISHKARA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/08_AVISHKARA/</guid>
      <description>One of my friends once asked me, “Is there ever one moment of the day when you are not doing Avishkara?” What could I tell him? Does he know the wonderful joy of Avishkara? He can’t imagine it because he does not really know how to love.
AVISHKARA
When I say that spirits can be helpful, I am sure you cannot imagine all the ramifications of such a statement. Let me explain it in this way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 SEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/09_SEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/09_SEX/</guid>
      <description>I have always maintained that there are two parts of the body which move even though they have no bone to support them: the tongue and the penis (or clitoris). These organs are made to move by the ego alone. They can take you to the heights of success if they are controlled, and if they are misused — if you make just a single mistake in your sadhana — down you go, divebombing like a Stuka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 GIRNAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/10_GIRNAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/1_left-hand/10_GIRNAR/</guid>
      <description>Human beings are nothing but sheep. I used to be in the flock of sheep, but I ran away, so it’s no surprise that everyone else, all the so-called normal people, thinks I’m insane or, at the least, abnormal. And I think the same about them. Only one of us can be right.
GIRNAR
I’ve always believed that when you do a thing you should forget everything else and do that one thing with heart and soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
