<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Jones William on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Jones William on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discourse 3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/discourse_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/discourse_3/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
THE WORK S OF SIR WILLIAM JONES.
IN SIX VOLUMES.
VOL. I.
PRINTED FOR G. G. AND J. ROBINSON, PATER-NOSTER-ROW; AND R. H. EVANS (SUCCESSOR TO MR. EDWARDS), NO. 26, PALL-MALL.
LONDON: MDCCXCIX.
ANNIVERSARY DISCOURSE, BY THE PRESIDENT.
IN the former discourses, which I had the honour of addressing to you, Gentlemen, on the institution and objects of our Society, I confined myself purposely to general topicks; giving in the first a distant proSpect of the vast career, on which we were entering, and, in the second, exhibiting a more diffuse, but still superficial, sketch of the various discoveries in History, Science, and Art, which we might justly expect from our inquiries into the literature of Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memoirs</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/memoirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/indologist/jones-william/memoirs/</guid>
      <description>MEMOIRS OF THE LIFE, WRITINGS And correSPONDENCE, OF
SIXTH EDITION. BY LORD TEIGNMOUTH. Manborr PRINTED FOR J. HATCHARD, BOOKSELLER TO THE QUEEN, 19; OPPOSITE ALBANY, PICCADILLY.. 1815, 1 M THE NLW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY [[580259]] ABTOR, 1* TIDEN H R [[1912]]
J. Brettell, Printer, Kupest Street, Haymarket, Londpl.:
TO LADY JONES. MADAM, I HAVE the honour to present to your Ladyship, the MEMOIRS of the LIFE OF SIR WILLIAM JONES; and it will afford me the sincerest pleasure to know, that the expectations which induced you to request me to undertake this work, have not been dissapointed by the perusal of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
