<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Law of Karma on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Law of Karma on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 STONEY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/01_STONEY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/01_STONEY/</guid>
      <description>“WHY DO YOU THINK I own horses and come to the race track?&amp;quot;
Vimalananda and I sat, in March 1977, on his usual bench in the First En closure of the Bombay Racecourse. We had reached there well in advance of the first race, and while we awaited the arrival of his colleagues, the friendly gamblers with whom he would wrangle, wager and roar, the man who was my mentor sprang this question on me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 ELAN</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/02_ELAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/02_ELAN/</guid>
      <description>I MET VIMALANANDA first in September 1975 on the day that Elan, one of his most reliable mares, won her first race for him. I first accompanied him to the races on the day of Stoney&amp;rsquo;s last outing. Horse racing began in Bombay in the early decades of the nineteenth century when a race ground emerged in what is now the predominantly Christian district of Byculla. When the time came to search for greener pastures, the Royal Western India Turf Club Limited (R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 TEASERS and STALLIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/03_TEASERS_and_STALLIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/03_TEASERS_and_STALLIONS/</guid>
      <description>BOMBAY&amp;rsquo;S SUMMER USUALLY begins near the end of March. With the summer of 1977 summer came the problem of where to send Stoney to brood. Pedigrees of all sorts fascinated Vimalananda; when we watched Wimbledon together he would sigh and say, “If only Jimmy Connors and Chrissy Evert would get together, their child would really be something!!” Now he had the opportunity to select the genes that would mingle with those of his beloved Stoney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 TIMIR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/04_TIMIR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/04_TIMIR/</guid>
      <description>IN EARLY 1978 I was introduced to Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s newest horse, a hand some compact colt named Timir, when I watched him win his first race. This occasion was also noteworthy for me—it was the first time I had been able to cheer home one of Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s horses..and I found winning to be as electrifying a feeling as he had promised it would be. For the first time I un derstood the seduction of that sensation, how for sporting types like Vima lananda each victory could be as thrilling as his first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 SCARLET RUBY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/05_SCARLET_RUBY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/05_SCARLET_RUBY/</guid>
      <description>STONEY FAILED TO GET into foal at Vitu Karve&amp;rsquo;s stud farm even in early 1978, due at least in part to Vitu&amp;rsquo;s unwillingness to spend much money on her feed. Vimalananda soon decided to send her elsewhere, but where? All the other stud farms insisted on seeing the color of his coin. When things seemed bleakest Nature stepped in, as She usually did for Vimalananda in a pinch. This time She arrived in the form of Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 THE CITY OF DELUSION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/06_THE_CITY_OF_DELUSION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/06_THE_CITY_OF_DELUSION/</guid>
      <description>AS BOMBAY&amp;rsquo;S IMPORTANCE in my life accelerated I increasingly under stood why Vimalananda had had to leave his life of many years as a itinerant sadhu and resettle in his hometown. Bombay was so crowded for him with tangled heaps of rnanubandhanas that nothing less than physical residence there would suffice for their unravelling. People daily arrived at his doorstep to confront him with shopping lists of cravings to be satisfied, but few of these solicitants showed any concern for him or his condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 REPAY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/07_REPAY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/07_REPAY/</guid>
      <description>OUR GREATEST TINGLE during the Spring 1979 Bombay Race Meeting was the announcement of a blessed event: the debut in our world of Stoney&amp;rsquo;s first foal, a colt whom Vimalananda promptly named Redstone. The spring&amp;rsquo;s most unusual incident, however, occurred midseason when Vimalananda felt obliged to exercise yet another of his siddhis to deal with Behram, the husband of Shernaz and father of Arzoo. He had unexpectedly and inoppor tunely arrived in Poona from Iran just in time for Navroz, the ancient Persian New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day which many Indian Zoroastrians still celebrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 REDSTONE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/08_REDSTONE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/08_REDSTONE/</guid>
      <description>VIMALANANDA&amp;rsquo;S INTEREST IN his spiritual children&amp;rsquo; had been corrod ing for some time, for they were proving to be no more dedicated than Shan karacharya&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;sons. It waned yet further on the morning that he had a visitation from Doshi&amp;rsquo;s wife. She and Doshi had come to Poona that weekend to accompany us for some homa nearby, and were staying in the hotel room that was next door to Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s. Apparently these two, conniving per haps with some of the other children, had decided that it was time for Vima lananda to part with some of his Tantric sexual knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 PRAKRITI SIDDHI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/09_PRAKRITI_SIDDHI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/09_PRAKRITI_SIDDHI/</guid>
      <description>HAD I KNOWN THEN what I know now of Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s Junior Guru Maharaj I would have concluded that in the act of awarding him the tran sient felicity of Redstone&amp;rsquo;s win Guru Maharaj had successfully stolen one of the few remaining joys from Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s life. Vimalananda, who must have suspected it all along, tried unsuccessfully to reveal this to me not long after the taxi-driver episode, during the course of an afternoon spent at Bhuleshwar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 EPILOGUE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/10_EPILOGUE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/3_law_of_karma/10_EPILOGUE/</guid>
      <description>THE FACTS OF VIMALANANDA&amp;rsquo;S dying are as easy to recount as they were tortuous to live through. Somehow I succeeded at cremating him at Bombay&amp;rsquo;s Banganga Smashan, just as eight years and three months previously he had prophesied that I would. And, just as he had promised all those years ago, his wife and children did not come to watch the pyre, for their egos still smarted from his failure to attend his daughter&amp;rsquo;s wedding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
