<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;AtmAnanda bio on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;AtmAnanda bio on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Intro to tantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/1_intro_to_tantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/1_intro_to_tantra/</guid>
      <description>Exposure to the Tantric Path
Chapter One
In that little town under the foothills of the western ghat in Kerala, there was just one real building which was a small temple with a tile roofing. The temple was surrounded by huts and shanties. When I arrived, there was a competition going on in the market place between two tantrics who had selected an onlooker from the crowd to be their medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 left hand secrets</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/2_left-hand-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/2_left-hand-secrets/</guid>
      <description>Chapter Two
When we met again, the tantra master was much more forthcoming. I was greeted with a warm embrace and invited to relax under the banyan tree. I sensed that I now belonged. In an awed voice I asked him, “What was it that I saw?”
He chuckled at my neophyte’s excitement. “So, you were impressed?” I nodded. “You saw Mohini, a demoness from the underworld. Had you known how, you could have entered a pact with her for the next cycle of Jupiter (twelve years).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 gate of dreams</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/3_gate_of_dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/3_gate_of_dreams/</guid>
      <description>Chapter Three
After three and a half years in Kerala I was transferred back to Tamil Nadu, to work under the rather severe chief accountant of the Salem branch, Mr. S. Venkata Subrahmanian. As it is common usage for educated English-speaking Tamils to be addressed by the first initials of their names, he was known to one and all as SVS.
My two good “same-age” friends were co-workers Vaidyanathan, serious, bespectacled and a bit shy, and Shankara Subrahmania, a jolly, big-bodied chap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 self in mirror</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/4_self_in_mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/4_self_in_mirror/</guid>
      <description>The Self in the Mirror
Chapter Four
The Chandogya Upanishad relates how Indra, king of the devas, and Virochana, king of the demons, both became students of the science of self-realization under Brahma. Brahma, to test them first, told them that the self was what they saw when they looked into a mirror or a pan of water. Virochana believed and went back to become a guru, teaching this to the other demons, who also believed; but Indra had second thoughts and returned to receive the true knowledge of the self as soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 again a mouse</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/5_again_a_mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/5_again_a_mouse/</guid>
      <description>Again a Mouse Mouse Background Information:
These stories are biographical narrations by the author, written down around 20 years ago. This was originally meant to be published as a book, but after completing the first eight chapters, the author chose not to continue, and thus we are left with the stories in their present incomplete form. Most of these stories took place around 1970. The areas discussed in these stories have changed greatly in the last 40 years and may not match what we see today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 becoming AtmAnanda</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/6_becoming_AtmAnanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/6_becoming_AtmAnanda/</guid>
      <description>I become ‘Swami Atmananda’ Posted by The Editor | Jul 10, 2010 | Mystical Experiences | 64,674 views
Atmananda Background Information:
These stories are biographical narrations by the author, written down around 20 years ago. This was originally meant to be published as a book, but after completing the first eight chapters, the author chose not to continue, and thus we are left with the stories in their present incomplete form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 sai bAbA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/7_sai-bAbA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/7_sai-bAbA/</guid>
      <description>With and Against Sai Baba
Chapter Seven
The first welcome I got upon my arrival at Sai Baba’s ashram was from a large group of ragged beggars sitting outside the front gate. Past them, flocks of well-off people crowded into the compound; that meant Sai Baba was here now. I viewed this scene with decidedly mixed feelings.
“He is supposed to be God”, I considered, “and his followers say he has the power to remove misfortune, disease and poverty – so why are these beggars loitering here just outside his own house?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Odd Gods of south</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/8_odd_Gods_of_south/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/misc/AtmAnanda-bio/8_odd_Gods_of_south/</guid>
      <description>Odd Gods of the South
Chapter Eight
A day or so later I asked my friend to take me around the village. We went to the Chitravati river, but since it was the dry season there was no water, just a sand channel.
On a rocky mound near the riverbed stood a tamarind tree from which Sai Baba is said to have magically plucked mangos and other fruits during his youth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
