<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;06 TANTRA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;06 TANTRA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Time, Eclipses and Nights</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/01_Time_Eclipses_and_Nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/01_Time_Eclipses_and_Nights/</guid>
      <description>In his youth Vimalananda had studied astrology with Jina Chandra Suri, and 1 frequently witnessed his amazing ability to cast an accurate horoscope from a visitor&amp;rsquo;s face alone. Though astrology is a respected means of diagno sis in Ayurveda it is no longer taught in Ayurvedic colleges, and I held out some hope that Vimalananda would teach me himself. But every time I asked for instruction he would refuse, saying, “You have more important things to learn right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Nyasa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/02_Nyasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/02_Nyasa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;But since right now I do know what time it is,” I said, “all these anustha nas and so on will not only help awaken my mantra but will also help me develop my devotion.”
“That&amp;rsquo;s right.” &amp;ldquo;Are there other practices I should know about?” I asked, knowing well that he expected me to continue asking even if I did not know what to ask.
&amp;ldquo;Well, there is nyasa. Very few people talk about nyasa, because so few people know about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Mental Worship</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/03_Mental_Worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/03_Mental_Worship/</guid>
      <description>“Now, although there are many different ways to worship, I have always believed it is best to worship mentally, if you can. Physical worship is always limited, especially now during Kali Yuga, when not even the experts are always able to do their physical worship properly. Even the most proficient devotee must occasionally make a mistake in his or her ritual; even the best trained mouth must sometimes mispronounce a mantra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Ganesha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/04_Ganesha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/06_TANTRA/04_Ganesha/</guid>
      <description>Vimalananda delivered the next in this series of musings at a Ganesha temple. I can no longer recall which temple it was, for he was very fond of Ganesha and we paid regular visits to several images of the elephant-headed god. The area around Poona has been associated with Ganesha worship for centuries, and Ganesha is still one of the most beloved of deities of that region.
After we had finished our worship and were relaxing, he began to address me thus:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
