<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 Book One on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 Book One on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/01/</guid>
      <description>The teachers of the purpose of existence. – Whether I regard human beings with a good or with an evil eye, I always find them engaged in a single task, each and every one of them: to do what benefits the preservation of the human race. Not from a feeling of love for the race, but simply because within them nothing is older, stronger, more inexorable and invincible than this instinct – because this instinct constitutes the essence of our species and herd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/02/</guid>
      <description>Intellectual conscience. – I keep having the same experience and keep resisting it anew each time; I do not want to believe it although I can grasp it as with my hands: the great majority lacks an intellectual conscience – indeed, it has often seemed to me as if someone requiring such a conscience would be as lonely in the most densely populated cities as he would be in the desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/03/</guid>
      <description>Noble and common. – For common natures all noble, magnanimous feelings appear to be inexpedient and therefore initially incredible: they give a wink when they hear of such things and seem to want to say, ‘Surely there must be some advantage involved; one cannot see through every wall’ – they are suspicious of the noble person, as if he were furtively seeking his advantage. If they become all too clearly convinced of the absence of selfish intentions and gains, they view the noble person as a kind of fool: they despise him in his pleasure and laugh at the sparkle in his eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/04/</guid>
      <description>What preserves the species. – The strongest and most evil spirits have so far done the most to advance humanity: time and again they rekindled the dozing passions – every ordered society puts the passions to sleep –, time and again they reawakened the sense of comparison, of contradiction, of delight in what is new, daring, unattempted; they forced men to pit opinion against opinion, ideal model against ideal model. Mostly by force of arms, by toppling boundary stones, by violating pieties – but also by means of new religions and moralities!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/05/</guid>
      <description>Unconditional duties. – All persons who feel that they need the strongest words and sounds, the most eloquent gestures and postures, in order to be effective at all – revolutionary politicians, socialists, preachers of repentance with or without Christianity, all of whom refuse to accept semi-successes: they all speak of ‘duties’, and indeed always of duties with an unconditional character – without such duties they would have no right to their great pathos; they know that quite well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/06/</guid>
      <description>Loss of dignity. – Reflection has lost all its dignity of form: we have made a laughing-stock of the ceremony and solemn gestures of reflection, and couldn’t stand an old-style wise man. We think too fast, while on our way somewhere, while walking or in the midst of all sorts of business, even when thinking of the most serious things; we need little preparation, not even much silence: it is as if we carried around in our heads an unstoppable machine that keeps working even under the most unfavourable circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/07/</guid>
      <description>Something for the industrious. – Anyone who now wishes to make a study of moral matters opens up for himself an immense field of work. All kinds of passions have to be thought through separately, pursued separately through ages, peoples, great and small individuals; their entire reason and all their evaluations and modes of illuminating things must be revealed! So far, all that has given colour to existence still lacks a history: where could you find a history of love, of avarice, of envy, of conscience, of piety, of cruelty?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/08/</guid>
      <description>Unconscious virtues. – All qualities of a person of which he is conscious – and especially those he supposes to be visible and plain to others also – are subject to laws of development entirely different from those qualities which are unknown or badly known to him, which conceal themselves by means of their subtlety even from the eye of a rather subtle observer and which know how to hide as if behind nothing at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/09/</guid>
      <description>Our eruptions. – Countless things that humanity acquired in earlier stages, but so feebly and embryonically that no one could tell that they had been acquired, suddenly emerge into the light much later, perhaps after centuries; meanwhile they have become strong and ripe. Some ages seem to lack completely some talent or virtue, just as some people do: but just wait for their children and grandchildren, if you have time to wait – they bring to light the inner qualities of their grandfathers, the qualities that their grandfathers themselves did not know about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/10/</guid>
      <description>A kind of atavism. – I prefer to understand the rare human beings of an age as suddenly appearing, late ghosts of past cultures and their powers: as atavisms of a people and its mores – that way one can really understand something about them! They now seem strange, rare, extraordinary; and whoever feels these powers in himself must nurse, defend, honor, and cultivate them against another world that resists them: and so he becomes either a great human being or a mad and eccentric one, unless he perishes too soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/11/</guid>
      <description>Consciousness (Bewußtsein)6 – Consciousness (Bewußtheit) is the latest development of the organic, and hence also its most unfinished and unrobust feature. Consciousness gives rise to countless mistakes that lead an animal or human being to perish sooner than necessary, ‘beyond destiny’, as Homer puts it.7 If the preserving alliance of the instincts were not so much more powerful, if it did not serve on the whole as a regulator, humanity would have to perish with open eyes of its misjudging and its fantasizing, of its lack of thoroughness and its incredulity – in short, of its consciousness; or rather, without the instincts, humanity would long have ceased to exist!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/12/</guid>
      <description>On the aim of science. – What? The final aim of science should be to give man as much pleasure and as little displeasure as possible? But what if pleasure and displeasure are so intertwined that whoever wants as much as possible of one must also have as much as possible of the other – that whoever wants to learn to ‘jubilate up to the heavens’ must also be prepared for ‘grief unto death’?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/13/</guid>
      <description>On the doctrine of the feeling of power. – Benefiting and hurting others are ways of exercising one’s power over them – that is all one wants in such cases! We hurt those to whom we need to make our power perceptible, for pain is a much more sensitive means to that end than pleasure: pain always asks for the cause, while pleasure is inclined to stop with itself and not look back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/14/</guid>
      <description>The things people call love. – Greed and love: such different feelings these terms evoke! And yet it could be the same instinct, named twice: once disparaged by those who already have, in whom the instinct has somewhat calmed down and who now fear for what they ‘have’; the other time seen from the standpoint of the unsatisfied, the thirsty, and therefore glorified as ‘good’. Our love of our neighbours – is it not a craving for new property?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/15/</guid>
      <description>From a distance. – This mountain makes the entire region it dominates attractive and significant in every way; having said this to ourselves for the hundredth time, we are so unreasonably and thankfully disposed toward it that we suppose that it, the bestower of such delight, must itself be the most delightful thing in the region – and so we climb it and are disappointed. Suddenly the mountain itself and the entire landscape around us, beneath us, seem to have lost their magic; we had forgotten that certain types of greatness, like certain types of goodness, want to be beheld only from a distance and always from below, not from above – only thus do they have an effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/16/</guid>
      <description>Over the footbridge. – When dealing with people who are bashful about their feelings, one has to be able to dissimulate; they feel a sudden hatred towards anyone who catches them in a tender or enthusiastic or elevated feeling, as if he had seen their secrets. If one wants to do them good in such moments, one should make them laugh or utter some cold, jocular sarcasm: then their feeling freezes and they regain power over themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/17/</guid>
      <description>Finding a motive for one’s poverty. – There is clearly no trick that enables us to turn a poor virtue into a rich and overflowing one, but we can surely reinterpret its poverty nicely into a necessity, so that its sight no longer offends us and we no longer make reproachful faces at fate on its account. That is what the wise gardener does when he places the poor little stream in his garden in the arms of a nymph and thus finds a motive for its poverty: and who wouldn’t need nymphs as he does?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/18/</guid>
      <description>Ancient pride. – The specific hue which nobility had in the ancient world is absent in ours because the ancient slave is absent from our sensibility. A Greek of noble descent found such immense intermediate stages and such a distance between his own height and that ultimate baseness that he could barely see the slave clearly any more: not even Plato could really see him. It is different with us, accustomed as we are to the doctrine of human equality, if not also to equality itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/19/</guid>
      <description>Evil. – Examine the lives of the best and the most fruitful people and peoples and ask yourselves whether a tree which is supposed to grow to a proud height could do without bad weather and storms: whether misfortune and exernal resistance, whether any kinds of hatred, jealousy, stubbornness, mistrust, hardness, greed, and violence do not belong to the favourable conditions without which any great growth even of virtue is scarcely possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/20/</guid>
      <description>The dignity of foolishness. – A few millennia further along the course set by the last century – and everything men do will display the highest prudence: but just that way prudence will lose all its dignity. Then it will, to be sure, be necessary to be prudent, but it will also be so commonplace and vulgar that even a moderately aristocratic taste will experience this necessity as a vulgarity. And just as a tyranny of truth and science could increase esteem for the lie, a tyranny of prudence could spur a new kind of nobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/21/</guid>
      <description>To the teachers of selflessness. – A person’s virtues are called good with respect to their presumed effects not on him but on us and society – the praise of virtues has always been far from ‘selfless’, far from ‘unegoistic’! For otherwise one would have had to recognize that the virtues (such as diligence, obedience, chastity, piety, justice) are mostly harmful to their possessors, being drives which dominate them all too violently and covetously and in no way let reason keep them in balance with the other drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/22/</guid>
      <description>*L’ordre du jour pour le roi.*12 – The day begins: let us begin to organize for this day the business and festivities of our most gracious master who is still deigning to repose. His majesty has bad weather today: we shall be careful not to call it bad; we shall not speak of the weather – but we shall be a bit more ceremonious about the business than would otherwise be necessary and a bit more festive about the festivities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/23/</guid>
      <description>The signs of corruption. – Consider the following signs of those states of society that are necessary from time to time and that are designated by the word ‘corruption’. As soon as corruption sets in anywhere, a colourful superstition takes over, and the previous common faith of a people becomes pale and powerless against it: for supersitition is free-spiritedness of the second rank – whoever succumbs to it selects certain forms and formulas that appeal to him and allows himself some freedom of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/24/</guid>
      <description>Different forms of dissatisfaction. – The weak and, as it were, feminine discontented types are those who are innovative at making life more beautiful and profound; the strong discontents – the men among them, to stick with the metaphor – are innovative at making it better and safer. The former show their weakness and femininity by gladly letting themselves be deceived from time to time and occasionally resting content with a bit of intoxication and gushing enthusiasm, though they can never be satisfied entirely and suffer from the incurability of their dissatisfaction; they are also the promoters of all who know how to procure opiates and narcotic consolations, and consequently they resent those who esteem physicians above priests – thus they assure the continuance of real distress!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/25/</guid>
      <description>Not predestined for knowledge. – There is a stupid humility that is by no means rare, and those afflicted with it are altogether unfit to become votaries of knowledge. For as soon as a person of this type perceives something striking, he turns on his heel, as it were, and says to himself, ‘You have made a mistake! Where were your senses? This cannot be the truth!’ And then, instead of looking and listening more keenly again, he runs away, as if intimidated, from the striking thing and tries to shake it from his mind as fast as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>26</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/26/</guid>
      <description>What is life? – Life – that is: continually shedding something that wants to die; Life – that is: being cruel and inexorable against anything that is growing weak and old in us, and not just in us. Life – therefore means: being devoid of respect for the dying, the wretched, the aged? Always being a murderer? And yet old Moses said: ‘Thou shalt not kill.’17</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/27/</guid>
      <description>The renouncer. – What does the renouncer do? He strives for a higher world, he wants to fly further and higher than all affirmers – he throws away much that would encumber his flight, including some things that are not valueless, not disagreeable to him: he sacrifices it to his desire for the heights. This sacrificing, this throwing away, is now precisely what alone becomes visible in him and leads people to call him the renouncer, and thus he stands before us, shrouded in his hood as if he were the soul of a hairshirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/28/</guid>
      <description>Harming with what is best in oneself. – At times our strengths propel us so far ahead that we can no longer stand our weaknesses and perish from them. We may even foresee this outcome and still will have it no other way. Thus we become hard against that within us that wants to be spared, and our greatness is also our mercilessness. Such an experience, for which we must in the end pay with our lives, is a parable for the whole effect of great human beings on others and on their age: precisely with what is best in them, with what only they can do, they destroy many who are weak, insecure, in the process of becoming, of willing, and thus they are harmful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/29/</guid>
      <description>The add-on-liars. – When people in France started to fight the Aristotelian unities18 and others consequently also started to defend them, one could see again something that is so often apparent but that people are loath to see: one lied to oneself, inventing reasons for these laws, simply to avoid admitting that one had become used to them and would no longer have it any other way. And that is what one does, and has always done, within every prevailing morality and religion: the reasons and intents behind habits are invented only when some people start attacking the habits and asking for reasons and intents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/30/</guid>
      <description>The comedy of the famous. – Famous men who need their fame, e.g. all politicians, never choose allies and friends without ulterior motives: from one they want a piece of the splendour and reflected splendour of his virtue; from another the fear-inspiring aspects of certain dubious qualities that everyone knows him to have; from another they steal the reputation of his idleness, his lying in the sun, because it serves their own ends to appear inattentive and sluggish at times – it conceals the fact that they actually lie in wait; now they need a visionary around; now an expert; now a thinker; now a pedant, as if he were their present self; but just as quickly they don’t need them any more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/31/</guid>
      <description>Trade and nobility. – Buying and selling are common by now, like the art of reading and writing; everyone has practised it, even if he is not a tradesman, and gets more practice at this technique every day – just as formerly, in the age of a more savage humanity, everyone was a hunter and practised the technique of hunting every day. In that age, hunting was common; but eventually it became a privilege and thereby lost its everyday and common character – because it stopped being necessary and became a thing of moods and luxury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/32/</guid>
      <description>Undesired disciples. – ‘What can I do with these two young men!’ cried an irritated philosopher who ‘corrupted’ the youth as Socrates once had done;19 they are unwelcome students. This one can’t say ‘no’ and the other one says ‘half and half’ about everything. If they adopted my doctrine, the first would suffer too much, for my way of thinking requires a warlike soul, a desire to hurt, a delight in saying no, a hard skin; he would languish from open and internal wounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>33</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/33/</guid>
      <description>Outside the lecture-room. – ‘In order to prove to you that man is fundamentally a good-natured animal, I would remind you of how credulous he has been for so long. Only now, quite late and after tremendous self-conquest, has he become a distrustful animal. Yes, man is now more evil than ever.’ I do not understand this: why should man be more distrustful and evil now? ‘Because he now has a science – needs a science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/34/</guid>
      <description>*Historia abscondita.*20 – Every great human being exerts a retroactive force: for his sake all of history is put on the scale again, and a thousand secrets of the past crawl out of their hiding places – into his sunshine. There is no telling what may yet become a part of history. Maybe the past is still essentially undiscovered! So many retroactive forces are still needed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/35/</guid>
      <description>Heresy and witchcraft. – To think otherwise than is customary is much less the effect of a superior intellect than of strong, evil inclinations – detaching, isolating, defiant, gloating, and malicious inclinations. Heresy is the adjunct of witchcraft and surely no more harmless and least of all anything venerable. Heretics and witches are two species of evil people; what they have in common is that they also feel evil but are impelled by an unconquerable lust to harm what is prevailing (people or opinions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/36/</guid>
      <description>Last words. – One will recall that the emperor Augustus, that frightful man who had as much self-control and who could be as silent as any wise Socrates, became indiscreet against himself with his last words: he let his mask fall for the first time when he made it clear that he had worn a mask and acted a comedy – he had played the father of the fatherland and the wisdom on the throne well enough to create the proper illusion!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/37/</guid>
      <description>Because of three errors. – One has promoted science during the last centuries partly because it was through science that one hoped best to understand God’s goodness and wisdom – the main motive in the soul of the great Englishmen (such as Newton);26 partly because one believed in the absolute usefulness of knowledge, especially in the most intimate affiliation between morality, knowledge, and happiness – the main motive in the soul of the French (such as Voltaire);27 and partly because one believed that in science one had and loved something selfless, harmless, self-sufficient, and truly innocent in which the evil drives of humanity had no part at all – the main motive in the soul of Spinoza,28who felt divine in attaining knowledge – in sum, because of three errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>38</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/38/</guid>
      <description>The explosive ones. – When one considers how the energy of young men needs to explode, one is not surprised to see them decide so unsubtly and so unselectively for this or that cause: what thrills them is the sight of the zeal surrounding a cause and, so to speak, the sight of the burning match – not the cause itself. The subtler seducers therefore know how to create in them the expectation of an explosion and to disregard justifying their cause: reasons are not the way to win over these powder kegs!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>39</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/39/</guid>
      <description>Changed taste. – Change in common taste is more important than that in opinions; opinions along with proofs, refutations, and the whole intellectual masquerade are only symptoms of a changed taste and most certainly not what they are so often taken to be, its causes. How does common taste change? Through individuals – powerful, influential, and without any sense of shame – who announce and tyrannically enforce their hoc est ridiculum, hoc est absurdum,29 i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>40</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/40/</guid>
      <description>On the lack of noble style. – Soldiers and leaders still have a far higher relation to one another than do workers and employers. So far at least, all cultures with a military basis are still high above so-called industrial culture: the latter in its present form is altogether the most vulgar form of existence that has ever been. Here it is simply the law of need operating: one wants to live and has to sell oneself, but one despises those who exploit this need and buy the worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>41</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/41/</guid>
      <description>Against remorse. – The thinker sees his own actions as experiments and questions, as seeking explanations of something: to him, success and failure are primarily answers. To be vexed or even to feel remorse because something goes wrong – he leaves that to those who act because they were ordered to do so and who expect a beating when his gracious lordship is not pleased with the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>42</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/42/</guid>
      <description>Work and boredom. – Seeking work for the sake of wages – in this, nearly all people in civilized countries are alike; to all of them, work is just a means and not itself the end, which is why they are unrefined in their choice of work, provided it yields an ample reward. Now there are rare individuals who would rather perish than work without taking pleasure in their work: they are choosy, hard to please, and have no use for ample rewards if the work is not itself the reward of rewards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>43</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/43/</guid>
      <description>What the laws betray. – It is a grave error to study a people’s penal code as if it were an expression of its character; the laws do not betray what a people is but rather what appears to it as foreign, strange, uncanny, outlandish. The laws concern the exceptions to the morality of custom (Sittlichkeit der Sitte)31, and the severest punishments are for things that accord with the customs of the neighbouring people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>44</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/44/</guid>
      <description>The supposed motives. – Important as it may be to know the motives from which humanity has acted so far, it might be even more essential to know the belief people had in this or that motive, i.e. what humanity has imagined and told itself to be the real lever of its conduct so far. For people’s inner happiness and misery has come to them depending on their belief in this or that motive – not through the actual motives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/45/</guid>
      <description>Epicurus.34 – Yes, I am proud to experience Epicurus’ character in a way unlike perhaps anyone else and to enjoy, in everything I hear and read of him, the happiness of the afternoon of antiquity: I see his eye gaze at a wide whitish sea, across shoreline rocks bathed in the sun, as large and small creatures play in its light, secure and calm like the light and his eye itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>46</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/46/</guid>
      <description>Our amazement. – It is a deep and fundamental stroke of luck that science discovers things that stand up under examination and that furnish the basis, again and again, for further discoveries – after all, it could be otherwise! Indeed, we are so convinced of the uncertainty and the fantastical quality of our judgements and of the eternal change of human laws and concepts that it actually amazes us how well the results of science stand up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>47</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/47/</guid>
      <description>On the suppression of the passions. – If one constantly forbids oneself the expression of the passions, as if that were something to be left for the ‘common’, coarser, middle-class, peasant types – i.e. if one wants to suppress not the passions themselves but only their language and gesture – one still attains in addition what one did not desire: the suppression of the passions themselves, at least their weakening and alteration – the most instructive example being furnished by the court of Louis XIV and everything that depended on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/48/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge of distress. – Perhaps nothing separates human beings or ages from each other more than the different degrees of their knowledge of distress – distress of the soul as well as of the body. Regarding the latter we moderns may well, in spite of our frailties and fragilities, be bunglers and dreamers owing to lack of ample first-hand experience, compared with an age of fear, the longest of all ages, when individuals had to protect themselves against violence and to that end had themselves to become men of violence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>49</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/49/</guid>
      <description>Magnanimity and related things. – Those paradoxical phenomena, like the sudden coldness in the behaviour of the emotional person, or the humour of the melancholy person, or above all magnanimity as a sudden renunciation of revenge or a satisfaction of envy, appear in people who have a powerful inner centrifugal force, in people of sudden satiety and sudden nausea. Their satisfactions are so quick and strong that they are immediately followed by weariness and aversion and a flight into the opposite taste: in this opposite, the cramp of feeling is resolved – in one person by sudden cold, in another by laughter, in a third by tears and self-sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/50/</guid>
      <description>The argument from growing solitary. – The reproach of conscience is weak in even the most conscientious people compared to the feeling: ‘This or that is against the morals (die gute Sitte) of your society.’ Even the strongest person still fears a cold look or a sneer on the face of those among whom and for whom he has been brought up. What is he really afraid of? Growing solitary! This is the argument that refutes even the best arguments for a person or a cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>51</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/51/</guid>
      <description>The sense of truth. – I approve of any form of scepticism to which I can reply, ‘Let’s try it!’ But I want to hear nothing more about all the things and questions that don’t admit of experiment. This is the limit of my ‘sense of truth’; for there, courage has lost its right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/52/</guid>
      <description>What others know about us. – What we know about ourselves and remember is not as decisive to our life’s happiness as it is believed to be. One day, what others know (or think they know) about us assails us – and then we realize that that is more powerful. It is easier to deal with a bad conscience than a bad reputation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>53</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/53/</guid>
      <description>Where the good begins. – At the point where the poor power of the eye is no longer able to see the evil drive as such, owing to its increasing subtlety, man posits the realm of goodness; and the feeling of now having stepped into the land of goodness excites all those impulses that had been threatened and limited by the evil drive, such as the feeling of security, of comfort, of benevolence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>54</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/54/</guid>
      <description>The consciousness of appearance. – How wonderful and new and yet how fearful and ironic my new insight makes me feel towards all of existence! I have discovered for myself that the ancient humanity and animality, indeed the whole prehistory and past of all sentient being, continues within me to fabulate, to love, to hate, and to infer – I suddenly awoke in the middle of this dream, but only to the consciousness that I am dreaming and that I must go on dreaming lest I perish – as the sleepwalker has to go on dreaming in order to avoid falling down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>55</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/55/</guid>
      <description>The ultimate noblemindedness. – So what makes a person ‘noble’? Certainly not making sacrifices; even those burning with lust make sacrifices. Certainly not following some passion, for there are contemptible passions. Certainly not that one does something for others without selfishness: perhaps no one is more consistently selfish than the noble one. – Rather, the passion that overcomes the noble one is a singularity, and he fails to realize this: the use of a rare and singular standard and almost a madness; the feeling of heat in things that feel cold to everyone else; a hitting upon values for which the scale has not yet been invented; a sacrifice on altars made for an unknown god; a courage without any desire for honours; a self-sufficiency that overflows and communicates to men and things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>56</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/1_Book_One/56/</guid>
      <description>The desire for suffering. – When I think of the desire to do something, how it continually tickles and goads the millions of young Europeans who cannot endure boredom and themselves, I realize that they must have a yearning to suffer something in order to make their suffering a likely reason for action, for deeds. Neediness is needed! Hence the clamour of the politicians; hence the many false, fictitious, exaggerated ‘emergencies’ of all kinds and the blind readiness to believe in them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
