<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;anUShA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;anUShA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AShTAvakra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/aShTAvakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/aShTAvakra/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Drown the politics, please, not our young people
You might know of Nachiketa as the brave boy who impressed Yama, the god of death, with his persistence in his pursuit of the truth. So here is the story of Ashtavakra, who, as a young man, impressed scores of scholars with his wisdom and his quest for justice.
The rapid closing down of multiple illegal coaching centres in the basements of New Delhi after students lost their lives in a flooding incident is too little, too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrology - narmamAlA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/astrology_narmamAlA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/astrology_narmamAlA/</guid>
      <description>The fault, dear Brutus, is not…
Sans the Sacred
Anusha S Rao
With the election results now out, and all the politicians of competing formations scrambling to present a united front, it is time to think about how the exit polls were so wildly off-mark. All the political analysts are welcome to think about why the exit polls were misleading, and why the BJP’s campaign backfired &amp;ndash; after all, hindsight is 20-20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HaMsAvalI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/haMsAvalI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/haMsAvalI/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Kate, wish you had read Hamsavali’s story, mate
Who will tell the British royals to carefully read the literature of the countries they once colonised?
Anusha S Rao
With Kate Middleton, the Princess of Wales, not having made a public appearance in a couple of months, everyone on social media is losing their mind, coming up with conspiracy theories as to where she might be and what she might be doing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MahAbhArata fraud</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/mahAbhArata-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/anUShA/mahAbhArata-fraud/</guid>
      <description>The ‘management lessons from Mahabharata’ fraud
Why look at such a rich tradition of literature to extract banal lessons on how to squeeze a little extra from your corporate job? Let us read stories for what they are and they will enchant us anew.
With all the news on the political front the same old, same old, perhaps you will allow me to indulge in a little tirade on one of my pet peeves &amp;ndash; courses on management techniques from the Bhagavad Gita.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
