<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;5 Book Five on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;5 Book Five on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>343</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/343/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/343/</guid>
      <description>How to understand our cheerfulness. – The greatest recent event – that ‘God is dead’; that the belief in the Christian God has become unbelievable – is already starting to cast its first shadow over Europe. To those few at least whose eyes – or the suspicion in whose eyes is strong and subtle enough for this spectacle, some kind of sun seems to have set; some old deep trust turned into doubt: to them, our world must appear more autumnal, more mistrustful, stranger, ‘older’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>344</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/344/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/344/</guid>
      <description>In what way we, too, are still pious. – In science, convictions have no right to citizenship, as one says with good reason: only when they decide to step down to the modesty of a hypothesis, a tentative experimental standpoint, a regulative fiction,1 may they be granted admission and even a certain value in the realm of knowledge – though always with the restriction that they remain under police supervision, under the police of mistrust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>345</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/345/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/345/</guid>
      <description>Morality as a problem. – The lack of personality always takes its revenge: a weakened, thin, extinguished personality, one that denies itself and its own existence, is no longer good for anything good – least of all for philosophy. ‘Selflessness’ has no value in heaven or on earth; all great problems demand great love, and only strong, round, secure minds who have a firm grip on themselves are capable of that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>346</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/346/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/346/</guid>
      <description>Our question mark. – But you do not understand this? Indeed, people will have trouble understanding us. We are searching for words, perhaps also for ears. Who are we anyway? If we simply called ourselves godless (to use an old expression), or unbelievers, or even immoralists, we would not think that these words came near to describing us: we are all three of them, at too advanced a stage for anyone to comprehend – for you to comprehend, my curious gentlemen – how it feels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>347</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/347/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/347/</guid>
      <description>Believers and their need to believe. – The extent to which one needs a faith in order to flourish, how much that is ‘firm’ and that one does not want shaken because one clings to it – that is a measure of the degree of one’s strength (or, to speak more clearly, one’s weakness). Christianity, it seems to me, is still needed by most people in old Europe even today; hence it still finds believers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>348</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/348/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/348/</guid>
      <description>On the origin of scholars. – In Europe the scholar grows out of all kinds of classes and social conditions like a plant that requires no particular kind of soil: thus he belongs, essentially and involuntarily, to the bearers of the democratic idea. But this origin betrays itself. Once one has somewhat trained one’s eye to recognize in a scholarly book, in a scientific treatise, the scholar’s intellectual idiosyncrasy – every scholar has one – and catch it in the act, one will almost always behind it come face to face with the scholar’s ‘prehistory’, his family, especially its occupations and crafts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>349</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/349/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/349/</guid>
      <description>Once again, the origin of the scholars. – To wish to preserve oneself is a sign of distress, of a limitation of the truly basic life-instinct, which aims at the expansion of power and in so doing often enough risks and sacrifices self-preservation. It is symptomatic that certain philosophers, such as the consumptive Spinoza, took and indeed had to take just the so-called self-preservation instinct to be decisive:9 – they were simply people in distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>350</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/350/</guid>
      <description>*In honour of the homines religiosi.*10 – The struggle against the church is certainly, among other things – for it means many things – also the struggle of the baser, meaner, more cheerful, more confiding, more superficial natures against the dominion of the graver, deeper, and more contemplative, that is, more evil and distrustful individuals who, with a long-standing suspicion about the value of existence, also brooded over their own worth: the base instinct of the people, its sensuality, its ‘good heart’, rebelled against them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>351</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/351/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/351/</guid>
      <description>In honour of the priestly type: – I think that what the people mean by wisdom (and who today is not ‘people’?) – that prudent, cowlike serenity, piety and country parson meekness which lies in the meadow and earnestly and ruminantly observes life – is also that from which precisely the philosophers have always felt the most remote, probably because they were not ‘people’ enough, not country parsons enough. They will presumably also be the last to learn to believe that the people might come to understand something of that which is most remote from them, something of the great passion of the knowledge-seeker who steadfastly lives, must live, in the thundercloud of the highest problems and the weightiest responsibilities (and thus in no way as an observer, outside, indifferent, secure, objective&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>352</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/352/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/352/</guid>
      <description>The extent to which morality is hardly dispensable. – The naked human being is generally a disgraceful sight – I am talking about us Europeans (and not even about female Europeans!). Supposing that by the mischievous trick of a sorcerer, the merriest dinner party suddenly saw itself exposed and undressed; I think not only the mirth would be lost but also the strongest appetite discouraged, – it seems we Europeans are utterly unable to dispense with that masquerade called clothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>353</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/353/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/353/</guid>
      <description>On the origin of religions. – The true invention of the religion-founders is first to establish a certain way of life and everyday customs that work as a disciplina voluntatis11 while at the same time removing boredom; and then to give just this life an interpretation that makes it appear illuminated by the highest worth, so that henceforth it becomes a good for which one fights and under certain circumstances even gives one’s life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>354</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/354/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/354/</guid>
      <description>On ‘the genius of the species’. – The problem of consciousness (or rather, of becoming conscious of something) first confronts us when we begin to realize how much we can do without it; and now we are brought to this initial realization by physiology and natural history (which have thus required two hundred years to catch up with Leibniz’s precocious suspicion).14 For we could think, feel, will, remember, and also ‘act’ in every sense of the term, and yet none of all this would have to ‘enter our consciousness’ (as one says figuratively).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>355</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/355/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/355/</guid>
      <description>The origin of our concept of ‘knowledge’. – I take this explanation from the street; I heard one of the common people say ‘he knew me right away’ – and I asked myself: what do the people actually take knowledge to be? what do they want when they want ‘knowledge’? Nothing more than this: something unfamiliar is to be traced back to something familiar. And we philosophers – have we really meant anything more by knowledge?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>356</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/356/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/356/</guid>
      <description>The extent to which things will become ever more ‘artistic’ in Europe. – Even today, in this transitional period in which so many forms of coercion have lost their power, the need to make a living still forces nearly all European men to adopt a particular role – their so-called profession. A few retain the freedom, an apparent freedom, to choose this role themselves; for most of them it is chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>357</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/357/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/357/</guid>
      <description>On the old problem: ‘What is German?’ – Add up for yourself the real achievements in philosophical thinking that can be attributed to Germans: is there any legitimate sense in which one can credit them to the entire race? Can we say that they are also the work of the ‘German soul’, or at least symptoms of it in the same sense in which we are accustomed to take Plato’s ideomania, his nearly religious lunacy about forms, as a development and testimony of ‘the Greek soul’?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>358</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/358/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/358/</guid>
      <description>The peasant rebellion of the spirit. – We Europeans confront a world of tremendous ruins. A few things are still towering; much looks decayed and uncanny, while most things are already lying on the ground: picturesque enough – where has one ever seen more beautiful ruins? – and overgrown by large and small weeds. The Church is this city of decline: we see the religious society of Christianity shaken to its lowest foundations; faith in God has collapsed; faith in the Christian-ascetic ideal is still fighting its last battle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>359</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/359/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/359/</guid>
      <description>The revenge against the spirit and other ulterior motives of morality. – Morality – where do you suppose that it finds its most dangerous and insidious advocates?&amp;hellip;There is a human being who has turned out badly, who does not have spirit enough to be able to enjoy it and just enough education to know this; bored, weary, a self-despiser; wealthy through inheritance, he is deprived even of the last comfort, ‘the blessings of work’, self-forgetfulness in ‘daily labour’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>360</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/360/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/360/</guid>
      <description>Two kinds of causes that are often confused. – This seems to me to be one of my most essential steps forward: I learned to distinguish the cause of acting from the cause of acting in a certain way, in a certain direction, with a certain goal. The first kind of cause is a quantum of dammed-up energy waiting to be used somehow, for something; the second kind, by contrast, is something quite insignificant, mostly a small accident in accordance with which this quantum ‘discharges’ itself in one particular way: the match versus the powder keg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>361</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/361/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/361/</guid>
      <description>On the problem of the actor. – The problem of the actor has troubled me for a very long time; I was unsure (and still sometimes am) whether it is only from this angle that one can approach the dangerous concept of the ‘artist’ – a concept that has heretofore been treated with unpardonable generosity. Falseness with a good conscience; the delight in pretence erupting as a power that pushes aside, floods, and at times extinguishes one’s so-called ‘character’; the inner longing for a role and mask, for an appearance (Schein); an excess of capacities for all kinds of adaptation that can no longer be satisfied in the service of the nearest, most narrowly construed utility – perhaps all of this is distinctive not only of the actor?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>362</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/362/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/362/</guid>
      <description>Our faith in the masculinization of Europe. – We owe it to Napoleon (and not at all to the French Revolution, which aimed at the ‘brotherhood’ of peoples and a general, blooming exchange of hearts) that a few warlike centuries, incomparable to any other in history, are likely to follow in succession – in short, that we have entered the classic age of war, of sophisticated yet popular war on the largest scale (in terms of weapons, talents, discipline); all coming ages will look back on this kind of war with envy and deep respect as something perfect, for the national movement out of which this war glory is growing is merely the countershock against Napoleon and would not exist without Napoleon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>363</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/363/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/363/</guid>
      <description>How each sex has its own prejudice about love. – Despite all the concessions I am willing to make to the prejudice favouring monogamy, I will never admit talk of equal rights for man and woman in love: there are none. For man and woman have different conceptions of love – and it belongs to the conditions of love in each sex that neither presupposes the same feeling, the same concept of ‘love’ in the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>364</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/364/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/364/</guid>
      <description>The hermit speaks. – The art of dealing with people depends essentially on the skill (requiring much practice) to accept and eat a meal prepared in a kitchen you don’t trust. If you come to the table ravenous, all is easy (‘the worst company makes itself felt’ – as Mephistopheles says);36 but one is never that hungry when one needs to be! Oh, how hard it is to digest one’s fellow men!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>365</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/365/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/365/</guid>
      <description>The hermit speaks again. – We, too, deal with ‘people’; we, too, modestly don the cloak in which (as which) others know us, respect us, seek us, and so we appear in company, i.e. among others who are disguised but don’t want to admit it. Like all clever masks we, too, politely prop up a chair against the door when confronted with curiosity about anything but our ‘cloak’. But there are other ways and tricks for ‘wandering amongst’, for ‘associating with’, people: for instance, as a ghost – which is highly advisable if one desires to get rid of them quickly and make them afraid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>366</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/366/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/366/</guid>
      <description>Faced with a scholarly book. – We are not among those who have ideas only between books, stimulated by books – our habit is to think outdoors, walking, jumping, climbing, dancing, preferably on lonely mountains or right by the sea where even the paths become thoughtful. Our first question about the value of a book, a person, or a piece of music is: ‘Can they walk?’ Even more, ‘Can they dance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>367</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/367/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/367/</guid>
      <description>The first distinction to draw regarding artworks. – Everything that is thought, written, painted, composed, even built and sculpted, belongs either to monologue art or to art before witnesses. The second category must also include the seemingly monologue art involving faith in God, the entire lyricism of prayer; for solitude does not yet exist to the pious – this invention was first made by us, the godless. I know no deeper distinction in an artist’s entire optics than this: whether he views his budding artwork (‘himself’) from the eye of the witness, or whether he ‘has forgotten the world’, which is the essential feature of all monologue art – it is based on forgetting; it is the music of forgetting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>368</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/368/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/368/</guid>
      <description>The cynic speaks. – My objections to Wagner’s music are physiological objections: why disguise them with aesthetic formulas? My ‘fact’ is that I stop breathing easily once this music starts affecting me; that my foot immediately gets angry at it and revolts – it has a need for tempo, dance, march; it demands chiefly from music the raptures found in good walking, striding, leaping, and dancing – but doesn’t my stomach protest, too?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>369</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/369/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/369/</guid>
      <description>Our coexistence. – Don’t we have to admit to ourselves, we artists, that there exists an uncanny disparity within us; that in an odd way our taste and on the other hand our creative power stand each distinct from the other; each remains the way it is by itself, and each grows by itself; I mean each of these has completely different degrees and tempi of old, young, ripe, overblown, rotten?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>370</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/370/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/370/</guid>
      <description>What is romanticism? – It may be recalled, at least among my friends, that initially I approached the modern world with a few crude errors and over-estimations and, in any case, with hope. I understood – on the basis of who knows what personal experiences? – the philosophical pessimism of the nineteenth century as if it were a symptom of a higher force of thought, of more audacious courage, and of more victorious fullness of life than had characterized the eighteenth century, the age of Hume, Kant, Condillac,39 and the sensualists: thus, tragic insight struck me as the distinctive luxury of our culture, its most precious, noblest and most dangerous squandering; but still, in view of its over-richness, as its permitted luxury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>371</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/371/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/371/</guid>
      <description>We incomprehensible ones. – Have we ever complained about being misunderstood, misjudged, misidentified, defamed, misheard, and ignored? This is precisely our lot – oh, for a long time yet! Let’s say until 1901, to be modest – this is also our distinction; we wouldn’t honour ourselves enough if we wanted it otherwise. We are misidentified – for we ourselves keep growing, changing, shedding old hides; we still shed our skins every spring; we become increasingly younger, more future-oriented, taller, stronger; we drive our roots ever more powerfully into the depths – into evil – while at the same time embracing the heavens ever more lovingly and broadly, and absorbing their light ever more thirstily with all our sprigs and leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>372</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/372/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/372/</guid>
      <description>Why we are not idealists. – Formerly, philosophers feared the senses: is it possible that we have unlearned this fear all too much? Today we are all sensualists, we philosophers of the present and future, not in theory but in praxis, in practice.45 The former, however, saw the senses as trying to lure them away from their world, from the cold kingdom of ‘ideas’, to a dangerous Southern isle where they feared their philosophers’ virtues would melt away like snow in the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>373</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/373/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/373/</guid>
      <description>‘Science’ as prejudice. – It follows from the laws that govern rank-ordering (Rangordnung) that scholars, insofar as they belong to the intellectual middle class, are not even allowed to catch sight of the truly great problems and question marks; moreover, their courage and eyes simply don’t reach that far – and above all, the need that makes them scholars, their inner expectations and wish that things might be such and such, their fear and hope, too soon find rest and satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>374</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/374/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/374/</guid>
      <description>Our new ‘infinite’. – How far the perspectival character of existence extends, or indeed whether it has any other character; whether an existence without interpretation, without ‘sense’, doesn’t become ‘nonsense’; whether, on the other hand, all existence isn’t essentially an interpreting existence – that cannot, as would be fair, be decided even by the most industrious and extremely conscientious analysis and self-examination of the intellect; for in the course of this analysis, the human intellect cannot avoid seeing itself under its perspectival forms, and solely in these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>375</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/375/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/375/</guid>
      <description>Why we seem to be Epicureans. – We are cautious, we modern men, about ultimate convictions; our mistrust lies in wait for the enchantments and deceptions of the conscience involved in every strong faith, every unconditional Yes and No. How can this be explained? Maybe what is to be found here is largely the caution of ‘once bitten, twice shy’; of the disappointed idealist; but there is also another, superior component: the gleeful curiosity of the one who used to stand in the corner and was driven to despair by his corner and who now delights and luxuriates in the opposite of a corner, in the boundless, in ‘the free as such’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>376</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/376/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/376/</guid>
      <description>Our slow periods. – This is how all artists and people of ‘works’ feel, the motherly type: at every chapter of their lives – which is always marked by a work – they always think they’ve reached their goal; they would always patiently take death with the feeling ‘we are ripe for it’. This is not the expression of weariness – rather that of a certain autumnal sunniness and mildness that the work itself, the fact that the work has become ripe, always leaves behind in its creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>377</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/377/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/377/</guid>
      <description>We who are homeless. – Among Europeans today there is no lack of those who have a right to call themselves homeless in a distinctive and honourable sense: it is to them in particular that I commend my secret wisdom and *gaya scienza.*50 For their lot is hard; their hope uncertain; it is a feat to invent a form of comfort for them – but to what avail! We children of the future – how could we be at home in this today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>378</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/378/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/378/</guid>
      <description>‘Andbecome bright again’. – We who are generous and rich in spirit, who stand by the road like open wells with no intention to fend off anyone who feels like drawing from us – we unfortunately do not know how to defend ourselves where we want to: we have no way of preventing people from clouding us, from darkening us; the time in which we live throws into us what is most time-bound; its dirty birds drop their filth into us; its boys their knick-knacks; and exhausted wanderers who come to us to rest, their small and great miseries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>379</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/379/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/379/</guid>
      <description>The fool’s interlude. – The writer of this book is no misanthrope; today one pays too dearly for hatred of man. In order to hate the way one formerly hated the human being, Timonically,53 wholly, without exception, with one’s whole heart, with the whole love of hatred, one would have to renounce contempt. And how much fine joy, how much patience, how much graciousness even do we owe precisely to our contempt!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>380</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/380/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/380/</guid>
      <description>‘The wanderer’ speaks. – In order to see our European morality for once as it looks from a distance, and to measure it up against other past or future moralities, one has to proceed like a wanderer who wants to know how high the towers in a town are: he leaves the town. ‘Thoughts about moral prejudices’, if they are not to be prejudices about prejudices, presuppose a position outside morality, some point beyond good and evil to which one has to rise, climb, or fly – and in the present case, at least a point beyond our good and evil, a freedom from everything ‘European’, by which I mean the sum of commanding value judgements that have become part of our flesh and blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>381</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/381/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/381/</guid>
      <description>On the question of being understandable. – One does not only wish to be understood when one writes; one wishes just as surely not to be understood. It is by no means necessarily an objection to a book when anyone finds it incomprehensible: perhaps that was part of the author’s intention – he didn’t want to be understood by just ‘anybody’. Every nobler spirit and taste selects his audience when he wants to communicate; in selecting it, he simultaneously erects barriers against ‘the others’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>382</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/382/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/382/</guid>
      <description>The great health. – We who are new, nameless, hard to understand; we premature births of an as yet unproved future – for a new end, we also need a new means, namely, a new health that is stronger, craftier, tougher, bolder, and more cheerful than any previous health. Anyone whose soul thirsts to experience the whole range of previous values and aspirations, to sail around all the coasts of this ‘inland sea’ (Mittelmeer) of ideals, anyone who wants to know from the adventures of his own experience how it feels to be the discoverer or conqueror of an ideal, or to be an artist, a saint, a lawmaker, a sage, a pious man, a soothsayer, an old-style divine loner – any such person needs one thing above all – the great health, a health that one doesn’t only have, but also acquires continually and must acquire because one gives it up again and again, and must give it up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>383</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/383/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/nietzsche/gay-science/5_Book_Five/383/</guid>
      <description>Epilogue. – But as I finally slowly, slowly paint this gloomy question mark and am still willing to remind my readers of the virtues of reading in the right way – oh, what forgotten and unknown virtues! – it strikes me that I hear all around myself most malicious, cheerful, hobgoblinlike laughter: the spirits of my book are themselves descending upon me, pulling my ears and calling me to order. ‘We can’t stand it anymore’, they shout, ‘stop, stop this raven-black music!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
