<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;04 SADHANA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;04 SADHANA on Vishvas&#39;s English lit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Khanda Manda Yoga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/01_Khanda_Manda_Yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/01_Khanda_Manda_Yoga/</guid>
      <description>Natural potential for spiritual development becomes valuable only by careful cultivation. All spiritual practices are sadhanas, but all sadhanas are not created equal. Vimalananda explains:
“The Rishis, India&amp;rsquo;s Seers, have understood our plight, and in their great magnanimity have created sadhanas by which we can extricate ourselves from our limitations and make progress. The Rishis have created many dif ferent sadhanas because there are so many different types of people, each of whom have special requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Name and Form</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/02_Name_and_Form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/02_Name_and_Form/</guid>
      <description>Every month or two, when the mood possessed him, Vimalananda would take me and Roshni with him to the Lakshmi-Narayana temple in Central Bombay, to look upon the face of God. The images in this temple are carved from pure white marble, and their sweetness and sublimity effortlessly pierce the hearts of those who gaze at them in faith. All the humans there the temple trustees, the priests, the watchmen&amp;ndash;knew Vimalananda, and all were happy to see him arrive, all except the musicians, who were envious of his superior musical abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 The Soma Yaga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/03_The_Soma_Yaga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/03_The_Soma_Yaga/</guid>
      <description>“If you are working to awaken your Kundalini and you try to do every thing on your own, you only need to make one slip and you are gone; but if · you worship and self-identify with a deity He or She will protect you when the energy becomes too strong for you to control. This is especially true if, like an Aghori, you are in a hurry to succeed, and you decide to practice dangerous sadhanas like Panchamakara.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 “Make Everything into a Sadhana&#34;</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/04_Make_Everything_into_a_Sadhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/04_Make_Everything_into_a_Sadhana/</guid>
      <description>“But I know you have said before that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to renounce every thing in order to achieve.&amp;quot;
“No, you don&amp;rsquo;t; but you do have to make everything into a sadhana. Offer every morsel of food to your deity; go to sleep at night remembering your deity. And as for sex, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to know any complicated sexual rituals in order to offer a mantra with each stroke of the penis into the fire of the vagina.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 The Sun, the Moon, and Fire</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/05_The_Sun_the_Moon_and_Fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/05_The_Sun_the_Moon_and_Fire/</guid>
      <description>During the afternoons Vimalananda&amp;rsquo;s conversation usually revolved around the racecourse, since most of the people who dropped by to see him at that time were interested in the hot tips which are the sustenance of those who gamble on horses. Those who were more interested in hearing him dis cuss spirituality would come in the evenings, when he would relax and let his mind focus on Reality. One night, after overhearing a couple of his spiri tual “children&amp;quot; speaking knowingly of “devotion” and “knowledge,” he felt a need to put the record straight:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Gayatri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/06_Gayatri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/english/prose/hindu/svoboda/aghora/2_kuNDalinI/04_SADHANA/06_Gayatri/</guid>
      <description>“Do you believe,” the visitor inquired, “that repeating Gayatri is a good thing?&amp;quot;
&amp;ldquo;I do smashan sadhana,” Vimalananda replied, “because I am fit for it,
(132)
SADHANA
and because it is fit for the age we live in. Some people, though, still try to perform sadhanas that were more appropriate for Satya Yuga. There are many people who claim to repeat the Gayatri Mantra, and claim to obtain all manner of believable and unbelievable benefits from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
